(function(){"use strict";var e={8115:function(e,t,n){var a=n(9242),o=n(3396);function i(e,t,n,a,i,r){const s=(0,o.up)("TechnicalExam");return(0,o.wg)(),(0,o.j4)(s)}var r=n(7139);const s={id:"control-panel",class:"container-lg d-print-none"},c={class:"navbar fixed-top navbar-light bg-light"},l={class:"container-lg"},h={class:"navbar-text"},u={class:"navbar-text"},d={class:"container-lg"},m=["id"],f=["id"];function p(e,t,n,i,p,g){const A=(0,o.up)("ExamQuestion");return(0,o.wg)(),(0,o.iD)(o.HY,null,[(0,o._)("div",s,[(0,o._)("nav",c,[(0,o._)("div",l,[(0,o._)("span",h,(0,r.zw)(g.examTitle),1),(0,o._)("span",u,(0,r.zw)(g.examDateRange),1),(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("span",{class:(0,r.C_)(["badge bg-success",{"bg-success":e.passed,"bg-danger":!e.passed}])},(0,r.zw)(e.correct_answers)+"/"+(0,r.zw)(e.total_questions)+" "+(0,r.zw)(e.passed?"Passed":"Failed"),3),[[a.F8,e.display_answers]]),(0,o._)("button",{onClick:t[0]||(t[0]=(...e)=>g.gradeExam&&g.gradeExam(...e))},"Grade")])])]),(0,o._)("div",d,[((0,o.wg)(!0),(0,o.iD)(o.HY,null,(0,o.Ko)(g.activeExamPool["subelements"],(e=>((0,o.wg)(),(0,o.iD)("section",{key:e,id:e},[((0,o.wg)(!0),(0,o.iD)(o.HY,null,(0,o.Ko)(g.activeExamPool[e]["section_groups"],(t=>((0,o.wg)(),(0,o.iD)("div",{key:t,id:t},[((0,o.wg)(!0),(0,o.iD)(o.HY,null,(0,o.Ko)(g.activeExamPool[e][t].questions,(e=>((0,o.wg)(),(0,o.j4)(A,{onSelectAnswer:g.onSelectAnswer,key:e,question:e.question,answer:e.answer,a:e.A,b:e.B,c:e.C,d:e.D},null,8,["onSelectAnswer","question","answer","a","b","c","d"])))),128))],8,f)))),128))],8,m)))),128))])],64)}var g=JSON.parse('{"exam_title":"FCC Exam Element 2 Question Pool for Technician Class","exam_effective_daterange":"Effective 7/01/2018-6/30/2022","exam_pool_release_date":"Errata #2 Release February 12,2018","subelements":["SUBELEMENT_T1","SUBELEMENT_T2","SUBELEMENT_T3","SUBELEMENT_T4","SUBELEMENT_T5","SUBELEMENT_T6","SUBELEMENT_T7","SUBELEMENT_T8","SUBELEMENT_T9","SUBELEMENT_T0"],"SUBELEMENT_T1":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T1 - FCC Rules, descriptions, and definitions for the Amateur Radio Service, operator and station license responsibilities - [6 Exam Questions - 6 Groups]","section_groups":["T1A","T1B","T1C","T1D","T1E","T1F"],"T1A":{"name":"T1A - Amateur Radio Service: purpose and permissible use of the Amateur Radio Service, operator/primary station license grant; Meanings of basic terms used in FCC rules; Interference; RACES rules; Phonetics; Frequency Coordinator","questions":[{"answer":"T1A01 (C) [97.1]","question":"Which of the following is a purpose of the Amateur Radio Service as stated in the FCC rules and regulations?","A":"A. Providing personal radio communications for as many citizens as possible","B":"B. Providing communications for international non-profit organizations","C":"C. Advancing skills in the technical and communication phases of the radio art","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1A02 (C) [97.1]","question":"Which agency regulates and enforces the rules for the Amateur Radio Service in the United States?","A":"A. FEMA","B":"B. Homeland Security","C":"C. The FCC","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1A03 (D) [97.119(b)(2)]","question":"What are the FCC rules regarding the use of a phonetic alphabet for station identification in the Amateur Radio Service?","A":"A. It is required when transmitting emergency messages","B":"B. It is prohibited","C":"C. It is required when in contact with foreign stations","D":"D. It is encouraged"},{"answer":"T1A04 (A) [97.5(b)(1)]","question":"How many operator/primary station license grants may be held by any one person?","A":"A. One","B":"B. No more than two","C":"C. One for each band on which the person plans to operate","D":"D. One for each permanent station location from which the person plans to operate"},{"answer":"T1A05 (C) [97.7]","question":"What is proof of possession of an FCC-issued operator/primary license grant?","A":"A. A printed operator/primary station license issued by the FCC must be displayed at the transmitter site","B":"B. The control operator must have an operator/primary station license in his or her possession when in control of a transmitter","C":"C. The control operator\'s operator/primary station license must appear in the FCC ULS consolidated licensee database","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1A06 (C) [97.3(a)(9)]","question":"What is the FCC Part 97 definition of a beacon?","A":"A. A government transmitter marking the amateur radio band edges","B":"B. A bulletin sent by the FCC to announce a national emergency","C":"C. An amateur station transmitting communications for the purposes of observing propagation or related experimental activities","D":"D. A continuous transmission of weather information authorized in the amateur bands by the National Weather Service"},{"answer":"T1A07 (C) [97.3(a)(41)]","question":"What is the FCC Part 97 definition of a space station?","A":"A. Any satellite orbiting the earth","B":"B. A manned satellite orbiting the earth","C":"C. An amateur station located more than 50 km above the Earth\'s surface","D":"D. An amateur station using amateur radio satellites for relay of signals"},{"answer":"T1A08 (B) [97.3(a)(22)]","question":"Which of the following entities recommends transmit/receive channels and other parameters for auxiliary and repeater stations?","A":"A. Frequency Spectrum Manager appointed by the FCC","B":"B. Volunteer Frequency Coordinator recognized by local amateurs","C":"C. FCC Regional Field Office","D":"D. International Telecommunications Union"},{"answer":"T1A09 (C) [97.3(a)(22)]","question":"Who selects a Frequency Coordinator?","A":"A. The FCC Office of Spectrum Management and Coordination Policy","B":"B. The local chapter of the Office of National Council of Independent Frequency Coordinators","C":"C. Amateur operators in a local or regional area whose stations are eligible to be repeater or auxiliary stations","D":"D. FCC Regional Field Office"},{"answer":"T1A10 (D) [97.3(a)(38), 97.407]","question":"Which of the following describes the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service (RACES)?","A":"A. A radio service using amateur frequencies for emergency management or civil defense communications","B":"B. A radio service using amateur stations for emergency management or civil defense communications","C":"C. An emergency service using amateur operators certified by a civil defense organization as being enrolled in that organization","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1A11 (B) [97.101 (d)]","question":"When is willful interference to other amateur radio stations permitted?","A":"A. To stop another amateur station which is breaking the FCC rules","B":"B. At no time","C":"C. When making short test transmissions","D":"D. At any time, stations in the Amateur Radio Service are not protected from willful interference"}]},"T1B":{"section_name":"T1B - Authorized frequencies: frequency allocations; ITU; emission modes; restricted sub-bands; spectrum sharing; transmissions near band edges; contacting the International Space Station; power output","questions":[{"answer":"T1B01 (B)","question":"What is the International Telecommunications Union (ITU)?","A":"A. An agency of the United States Department of Telecommunications Management","B":"B. A United Nations agency for information and communication technology issues","C":"C. An independent frequency coordination agency","D":"D. A department of the FCC"},{"answer":"T1B02 (B) [97.301, 97.207(c)]","question":"Which amateur radio stations may make contact with an amateur radio station on the International Space Station (ISS) using 2 meter and 70 cm band frequencies?","A":"A. Only members of amateur radio clubs at NASA facilities","B":"B. Any amateur holding a Technician or higher-class license","C":"C. Only the astronaut\'s family members who are hams","D":"D. Contacts with the ISS are not permitted on amateur radio frequencies"},{"answer":"T1B03 (B) [97.301(a)]","question":"Which frequency is within the 6 meter amateur band?","A":"A. 49.00 MHz","B":"B. 52.525 MHz","C":"C. 28.50 MHz","D":"D. 222.15 MHz"},{"answer":"T1B04 (A) [97.301(a)]","question":"Which amateur band are you using when your station is transmitting on 146.52 MHz?","A":"A. 2 meter band","B":"B. 20 meter band","C":"C. 14 meter band","D":"D. 6 meter band"},{"answer":"T1B05 (B) [97.305(c)]","question":"What is the limitation for emissions on the frequencies between 219 and 220 MHz?","A":"A. Spread spectrum only","B":"B. Fixed digital message forwarding systems only","C":"C. Emergency traffic only","D":"D. Fast-scan television only"},{"answer":"T1B06 (B) [97.301(e), 97.305]","question":"On which HF bands does a Technician class operator have phone privileges?","A":"A. None","B":"B. 10 meter band only","C":"C. 80 meter, 40 meter, 15 meter and 10 meter bands","D":"D. 30 meter band only"},{"answer":"T1B07 (A) [97.305(a), (c)]","question":"Which of the following VHF/UHF frequency ranges are limited to CW only?","A":"A. 50.0 MHz to 50.1 MHz and 144.0 MHz to 144.1 MHz","B":"B. 219 MHz to 220 MHz and 420.0 MHz to 420.1 MHz","C":"C. 902.0 MHz to 902.1 MHZ","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1B08 (A) [97.303]","question":"Which of the following is a result of the fact that the Amateur Radio Service is secondary in all or portions of some amateur bands (such as portions of the 70 cm band)?","A":"A. U.S. amateurs may find non-amateur stations in those portions, and must avoid interfering with them","B":"B. U.S. amateurs must give foreign amateur stations priority in those portions","C":"C. International communications are not permitted in those portions","D":"D. Digital transmissions are not permitted in those portions"},{"answer":"T1B09 (D) [97.101(a), 97.301(a-e)]","question":"Why should you not set your transmit frequency to be exactly at the edge of an amateur band or sub-band?","A":"A. To allow for calibration error in the transmitter frequency display","B":"B. So that modulation sidebands do not extend beyond the band edge","C":"C. To allow for transmitter frequency drift","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1B10 (D) [97.301(e), 97.305(c)]","question":"Which of the following HF bands have frequencies available to the Technician class operator for RTTY and data transmissions?","A":"A. 10 meter, 12 meter, 17 meter, and 40 meter bands","B":"B. 10 meter, 15 meter, 40 meter, and 80 meter bands","C":"C. 30 meter band only","D":"D. 10 meter band only"},{"answer":"T1B11 (A) [97.313]","question":"What is the maximum peak envelope power output for Technician class operators using their assigned portions of the HF bands?","A":"A. 200 watts","B":"B. 100 watts","C":"C. 50 watts","D":"D. 10 watts"},{"answer":"T1B12 (D) [97.313(b)]","question":"Except for some specific restrictions, what is the maximum peak envelope power output for Technician class operators using frequencies above 30 MHz?","A":"A. 50 watts","B":"B. 100 watts","C":"C. 500 watts","D":"D. 1500 watts"}]},"T1C":{"section_name":"T1C - Operator licensing: operator classes; sequential and vanity call sign systems; international communications; reciprocal operation; places where the Amateur Radio Service is regulated by the FCC; name and address on FCC license database; license term; renewal; grace period","questions":[{"answer":"T1C01 (D) [97.9(a), 97.17(a)]","question":"For which license classes are new licenses currently available from the FCC?","A":"A. Novice, Technician, General, Advanced","B":"B. Technician, Technician Plus, General, Advanced","C":"C. Novice, Technician Plus, General, Advanced","D":"D. Technician, General, Amateur Extra"},{"answer":"T1C02 (D) [97.19]","question":"Who may select a desired call sign under the vanity call sign rules?","A":"A. Only a licensed amateur with a General or Amateur Extra class license","B":"B. Only a licensed amateur with an Amateur Extra class license","C":"C. Only a licensed amateur who has been licensed continuously for more than 10 years","D":"D. Any licensed amateur"},{"answer":"T1C03 (A) [97.117]","question":"What types of international communications is an FCC-licensed amateur radio station permitted to make?","A":"A. Communications incidental to the purposes of the Amateur Radio Service and remarks of a personal character","B":"B. Communications incidental to conducting business or remarks of a personal nature","C":"C. Only communications incidental to contest exchanges, all other communications are prohibited","D":"D. Any communications that would be permitted by an international broadcast station"},{"answer":"T1C04 (A) [97.107]","question":"When are you allowed to operate your amateur station in a foreign country?","A":"A. When the foreign country authorizes it","B":"B. When there is a mutual agreement allowing third party communications","C":"C. When authorization permits amateur communications in a foreign language","D":"D. When you are communicating with non-licensed individuals in another country"},{"answer":"T1C05 (A)","question":"Which of the following is a valid call sign for a Technician class amateur radio station?","A":"A. K1XXX","B":"B. KA1X","C":"C. W1XX","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1C06 (D) [97.5(a)(2)]","question":"From which of the following locations may an FCC-licensed amateur station transmit?","A":"A. From within any country that belongs to the International Telecommunications Union","B":"B. From within any country that is a member of the United Nations","C":"C. From anywhere within International Telecommunications Union (ITU) Regions 2 and 3","D":"D. From any vessel or craft located in international waters and documented or registered in the United States"},{"answer":"T1C07 (B) [97.23]","question":"What may result when correspondence from the FCC is returned as undeliverable because the grantee failed to provide and maintain a correct mailing address with the FCC?","A":"A. Fine or imprisonment","B":"B. Revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license","C":"C. Require the licensee to be re-examined","D":"D. A reduction of one rank in operator class"},{"answer":"T1C08 (C) [97.25]","question":"What is the normal term for an FCC-issued primary station/operator amateur radio license grant?","A":"A. Five years","B":"B. Life","C":"C. Ten years","D":"D. Twenty years"},{"answer":"T1C09 (A) [97.21(a)(b)]","question":"What is the grace period following the expiration of an amateur license within which the license may be renewed?","A":"A. Two years","B":"B. Three years","C":"C. Five years","D":"D. Ten years"},{"answer":"T1C10 (C) [97.5a]","question":"How soon after passing the examination for your first amateur radio license may you operate a transmitter on an Amateur Radio Service frequency?","A":"A. Immediately","B":"B. 30 days after the test date","C":"C. As soon as your operator/station license grant appears in the FCC’s license database","D":"D. You must wait until you receive your license in the mail from the FCC"},{"answer":"T1C11 (A) [97.21(b)]","question":"If your license has expired and is still within the allowable grace period, may you continue to operate a transmitter on Amateur Radio Service frequencies?","A":"A. No, transmitting is not allowed until the FCC license database shows that the license has been renewed","B":"B. Yes, but only if you identify using the suffix GP","C":"C. Yes, but only during authorized nets","D":"D. Yes, for up to two years"}]},"T1D":{"section_name":"T1D - Authorized and prohibited transmission: communications with other countries; music; exchange of information with other services; indecent language; compensation for use of station; retransmission of other amateur signals; codes and ciphers; sale of equipment; unidentified transmissions; one-way transmission","questions":[{"answer":"T1D01 (A) [97.111(a)(1)]","question":"With which countries are FCC-licensed amateur radio stations prohibited from exchanging communications?","A":"A. Any country whose administration has notified the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) that it objects to such communications","B":"B. Any country whose administration has notified the American Radio Relay League (ARRL) that it objects to such communications","C":"C. Any country engaged in hostilities with another country","D":"D. Any country in violation of the War Powers Act of 1934"},{"answer":"T1D02 (B) [97.113(b),97.111(b)]","question":"Under which of the following circumstances may an amateur radio station make one-way transmissions?","A":"A. Under no circumstances","B":"B. When transmitting code practice, information bulletins, or transmissions necessary to provide emergency communications","C":"C. At any time, as long as no music is transmitted","D":"D. At any time, as long as the material being transmitted did not originate from a commercial broadcast station"},{"answer":"T1D03 (C) [97.211(b), 97.215(b), 97.114(a)(4)]","question":"When is it permissible to transmit messages encoded to hide their meaning?","A":"A. Only during contests","B":"B. Only when operating mobile","C":"C. Only when transmitting control commands to space stations or radio control craft","D":"D. Only when frequencies above 1280 MHz are used"},{"answer":"T1D04 (A) [97.113(a)(4), 97.113(c)]","question":"Under what conditions is an amateur station authorized to transmit music using a phone emission?","A":"A. When incidental to an authorized retransmission of manned spacecraft communications","B":"B. When the music produces no spurious emissions","C":"C. When the purpose is to interfere with an illegal transmission","D":"D. When the music is transmitted above 1280 MHz"},{"answer":"T1D05 (A) [97.113(a)(3)(ii)]","question":"When may amateur radio operators use their stations to notify other amateurs of the availability of equipment for sale or trade?","A":"A. When the equipment is normally used in an amateur station and such activity is not conducted on a regular basis","B":"B. When the asking price is $100.00 or less","C":"C. When the asking price is less than its appraised value","D":"D. When the equipment is not the personal property of either the station licensee or the control operator or their close relatives"},{"answer":"T1D06 (B) [97.113(a)(4)]","question":"What, if any, are the restrictions concerning transmission of language that may be considered indecent or obscene?","A":"A. The FCC maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies","B":"B. Any such language is prohibited","C":"C. The ITU maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies","D":"D. There is no such prohibition"},{"answer":"T1D07 (B) [97.113(d)]","question":"What types of amateur stations can automatically retransmit the signals of other amateur stations?","A":"A. Auxiliary, beacon, or Earth stations","B":"B. Repeater, auxiliary, or space stations","C":"C. Beacon, repeater, or space stations","D":"D. Earth, repeater, or space stations"},{"answer":"T1D08 (B) [97.113(a)(3)(iii)]","question":"In which of the following circumstances may the control operator of an amateur station receive compensation for operating that station?","A":"A. When the communication is related to the sale of amateur equipment by the control operator\'s employer","B":"B. When the communication is incidental to classroom instruction at an educational institution","C":"C. When the communication is made to obtain emergency information for a local broadcast station","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1D09 (A) [97.113(5)(b)]","question":"Under which of the following circumstances are amateur stations authorized to transmit signals related to broadcasting, program production, or news gathering, assuming no other means is available?","A":"A. Only where such communications directly relate to the immediate safety of human life or protection of property","B":"B. Only when broadcasting communications to or from the space shuttle","C":"C. Only where noncommercial programming is gathered and supplied exclusively to the National Public Radio network","D":"D. Only when using amateur repeaters linked to the internet"},{"answer":"T1D10 (D) [97.3(a)(10)]","question":"What is the meaning of the term broadcasting in the FCC rules for the Amateur Radio Service?","A":"A. Two-way transmissions by amateur stations","B":"B. Transmission of music","C":"C. Transmission of messages directed only to amateur operators","D":"D. Transmissions intended for reception by the general public"},{"answer":"T1D11 (D) [97.119(a)]","question":"When may an amateur station transmit without on-the-air identification?","A":"A. When the transmissions are of a brief nature to make station adjustments","B":"B. When the transmissions are unmodulated","C":"C. When the transmitted power level is below 1 watt","D":"D. When transmitting signals to control model craft"}]},"T1E":{"section_name":"T1E - Control operator and control types: control operator required; eligibility; designation of control operator; privileges and duties; control point; local, automatic and remote control; location of control operator","questions":[{"answer":"T1E01 (D) [97.7(a)]","question":"When is an amateur station permitted to transmit without a control operator?","A":"A. When using automatic control, such as in the case of a repeater","B":"B. When the station licensee is away and another licensed amateur is using the station","C":"C. When the transmitting station is an auxiliary station","D":"D. Never"},{"answer":"T1E02 (D) [97.301, 97.207(c)]","question":"Who may be the control operator of a station communicating through an amateur satellite or space station?","A":"A. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator","B":"B. A General class or higher licensee who has a satellite operator certification","C":"C. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator who is also an AMSAT member","D":"D. Any amateur whose license privileges allow them to transmit on the satellite uplink frequency"},{"answer":"T1E03 (A) [97.103(b)]","question":"Who must designate the station control operator?","A":"A. The station licensee","B":"B. The FCC","C":"C. The frequency coordinator","D":"D. The ITU"},{"answer":"T1E04 (D) [97.103(b)]","question":"What determines the transmitting privileges of an amateur station?","A":"A. The frequency authorized by the frequency coordinator","B":"B. The frequencies printed on the license grant","C":"C. The highest class of operator license held by anyone on the premises","D":"D. The class of operator license held by the control operator"},{"answer":"T1E05 (C) [97.3(a)(14)]","question":"What is an amateur station control point?","A":"A. The location of the station’s transmitting antenna","B":"B. The location of the station transmitting apparatus","C":"C. The location at which the control operator function is performed","D":"D. The mailing address of the station licensee"},{"answer":"T1E06 (A) [97.301]","question":"When, under normal circumstances, may a Technician class licensee be the control operator of a station operating in an exclusive Amateur Extra class operator segment of the amateur bands?","A":"A. At no time","B":"B. When operating a special event station","C":"C. As part of a multi-operator contest team","D":"D. When using a club station whose trustee is an Amateur Extra class operator licensee"},{"answer":"T1E07 (D) [97.103(a)]","question":"When the control operator is not the station licensee, who is responsible for the proper operation of the station?","A":"A. All licensed amateurs who are present at the operation","B":"B. Only the station licensee","C":"C. Only the control operator","D":"D. The control operator and the station licensee are equally responsible"},{"answer":"T1E08 (A) [97.3(a)(6), 97.205(d)]","question":"Which of the following is an example of automatic control?","A":"A. Repeater operation","B":"B. Controlling the station over the internet","C":"C. Using a computer or other device to send CW automatically","D":"D. Using a computer or other device to identify automatically"},{"answer":"T1E09 (D) [97.109(c)]","question":"Which of the following is true of remote control operation?","A":"A. The control operator must be at the control point","B":"B. A control operator is required at all times","C":"C. The control operator indirectly manipulates the controls","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1E10 (B) [97.3(a)(39)]","question":"Which of the following is an example of remote control as defined in Part 97?","A":"A. Repeater operation","B":"B. Operating the station over the internet","C":"C. Controlling a model aircraft, boat, or car by amateur radio","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1E11 (D) [97.103(a)]","question":"Who does the FCC presume to be the control operator of an amateur station, unless documentation to the contrary is in the station records?","A":"A. The station custodian","B":"B. The third-party participant","C":"C. The person operating the station equipment","D":"D. The station licensee"}]},"T1F":{"section_name":"T1F - Station identification; repeaters; third-party communications; club stations; FCC inspection","questions":[{"answer":"T1F01 (B) [97.103(c)]","question":"When must the station licensee make the station and its records available for FCC inspection?","A":"A. At any time ten days after notification by the FCC of such an inspection","B":"B. At any time upon request by an FCC representative","C":"C. Only after failing to comply with an FCC notice of violation","D":"D. Only when presented with a valid warrant by an FCC official or government agent"},{"answer":"T1F02 (C) [97.119 (a)]","question":"When using tactical identifiers such as “Race Headquarters” during a community service net operation, how often must your station transmit the station’s FCC-assigned call sign?","A":"A. Never, the tactical call is sufficient","B":"B. Once during every hour","C":"C. At the end of each communication and every ten minutes during a communication","D":"D. At the end of every transmission"},{"answer":"T1F03 (D) [97.119(a)]","question":"When is an amateur station required to transmit its assigned call sign?","A":"A. At the beginning of each contact, and every 10 minutes thereafter","B":"B. At least once during each transmission","C":"C. At least every 15 minutes during and at the end of a communication","D":"D. At least every 10 minutes during and at the end of a communication"},{"answer":"T1F04 (C) [97.119(b)(2)]","question":"Which of the following is an acceptable language to use for station identification when operating in a phone sub-band?","A":"A. Any language recognized by the United Nations","B":"B. Any language recognized by the ITU","C":"C. The English language","D":"D. English, French, or Spanish"},{"answer":"T1F05 (B) [97.119(b)(2)]","question":"What method of call sign identification is required for a station transmitting phone signals?","A":"A. Send the call sign followed by the indicator RPT","B":"B. Send the call sign using a CW or phone emission","C":"C. Send the call sign followed by the indicator R","D":"D. Send the call sign using only a phone emission"},{"answer":"T1F06 (D) [97.119(c)]","question":"Which of the following formats of a self-assigned indicator is acceptable when identifying using a phone transmission?","A":"A. KL7CC stroke W3","B":"B. KL7CC slant W3","C":"C. KL7CC slash W3","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1F07 (B) [97.115(a)(2)]","question":"Which of the following restrictions apply when a non-licensed person is allowed to speak to a foreign station using a station under the control of a Technician class control operator?","A":"A. The person must be a U.S. citizen","B":"B. The foreign station must be one with which the U.S. has a third-party agreement","C":"C. The licensed control operator must do the station identification","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T1F08 (A) [97.3(a)(47)]","question":"What is meant by the term Third Party Communications?","A":"A. A message from a control operator to another amateur station control operator on behalf of another person","B":"B. Amateur radio communications where three stations are in communications with one another","C":"C. Operation when the transmitting equipment is licensed to a person other than the control operator","D":"D. Temporary authorization for an unlicensed person to transmit on the amateur bands for technical experiments"},{"answer":"T1F09 (C) [97.3(a)(40)]","question":"What type of amateur station simultaneously retransmits the signal of another amateur station on a different channel or channels?","A":"A. Beacon station","B":"B. Earth station","C":"C. Repeater station","D":"D. Message forwarding station"},{"answer":"T1F10 (A) [97.205(g)]","question":"Who is accountable should a repeater inadvertently retransmit communications that violate the FCC rules?","A":"A. The control operator of the originating station","B":"B. The control operator of the repeater","C":"C. The owner of the repeater","D":"D. Both the originating station and the repeater owner"},{"answer":"T1F11 (B) [97.5(b)(2)]","question":"Which of the following is a requirement for the issuance of a club station license grant?","A":"A. The trustee must have an Amateur Extra class operator license grant","B":"B. The club must have at least four members","C":"C. The club must be registered with the American Radio Relay League","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T2":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T2 - Operating Procedures - [3 Exam Questions - 3 Groups]","section_groups":["T2A","T2B","T2C"],"T2A":{"name":"T2A - Station operation: choosing an operating frequency; calling another station; test transmissions; procedural signs; use of minimum power; choosing an operating frequency; band plans; calling frequencies; repeater offsets","questions":[{"answer":"T2A01 (B)","question":"Which of the following is a common repeater frequency offset in the 2 meter band?","A":"A. Plus or minus 5 MHz","B":"B. Plus or minus 600 kHz","C":"C. Plus or minus 500 kHz","D":"D. Plus or minus 1 MHz"},{"answer":"T2A02 (A)","question":"What is the national calling frequency for FM simplex operations in the 2 meter band?","A":"A. 146.520 MHz","B":"B. 145.000 MHz","C":"C. 432.100 MHz","D":"D. 446.000 MHz"},{"answer":"T2A03 (A)","question":"What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 70 cm band?","A":"A. Plus or minus 5 MHz","B":"B. Plus or minus 600 kHz","C":"C. Plus or minus 500 kHz","D":"D. Plus or minus 1 MHz"},{"answer":"T2A04 (B)","question":"What is an appropriate way to call another station on a repeater if you know the other station\'s call sign?","A":"A. Say \\"break, break,\\" then say the station\'s call sign","B":"B. Say the station\'s call sign, then identify with your call sign","C":"C. Say \\"CQ\\" three times, then the other station\'s call sign","D":"D. Wait for the station to call CQ, then answer it"},{"answer":"T2A05 (C)","question":"How should you respond to a station calling CQ?","A":"A. Transmit \\"CQ\\" followed by the other station’s call sign","B":"B. Transmit your call sign followed by the other station’s call sign","C":"C. Transmit the other station’s call sign followed by your call sign","D":"D. Transmit a signal report followed by your call sign"},{"answer":"T2A06 (A)","question":"Which of the following is required when making on-the-air test transmissions?","A":"A. Identify the transmitting station","B":"B. Conduct tests only between 10 p.m. and 6 a.m. local time","C":"C. Notify the FCC of the transmissions","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T2A07 (A)","question":"What is meant by \\"repeater offset?\\"","A":"A. The difference between a repeater’s transmit frequency and its receive frequency","B":"B. The repeater has a time delay to prevent interference","C":"C. The repeater station identification is done on a separate frequency","D":"D. The number of simultaneous transmit frequencies used by a repeater"},{"answer":"T2A08 (D)","question":"What is the meaning of the procedural signal “CQ”?","A":"A. Call on the quarter hour","B":"B. A new antenna is being tested (no station should answer)","C":"C. Only the called station should transmit","D":"D. Calling any station"},{"answer":"T2A09 (B)","question":"What brief statement indicates that you are listening on a repeater and looking for a contact?","A":"A. The words “Hello test” followed by your call sign","B":"B. Your call sign","C":"C. The repeater call sign followed by your call sign","D":"D. The letters “QSY” followed by your call sign"},{"answer":"T2A10 (A)","question":"What is a band plan, beyond the privileges established by the FCC?","A":"A. A voluntary guideline for using different modes or activities within an amateur band","B":"B. A mandated list of operating schedules","C":"C. A list of scheduled net frequencies","D":"D. A plan devised by a club to indicate frequency band usage"},{"answer":"T2A11 (C)","question":"What term describes an amateur station that is transmitting and receiving on the same frequency?","A":"A. Full duplex","B":"B. Diplex","C":"C. Simplex","D":"D. Multiplex"},{"answer":"T2A12 (D)","question":"Which of the following is a guideline when choosing an operating frequency for calling CQ?","A":"A. Listen first to be sure that no one else is using the frequency","B":"B. Ask if the frequency is in use","C":"C. Make sure you are in your assigned band","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"}]},"T2B":{"section_name":"T2B - VHF/UHF operating practices: SSB phone; FM repeater; simplex; splits and shifts; CTCSS; DTMF; tone squelch; carrier squelch; phonetics; operational problem resolution; Q signals","questions":[{"answer":"T2B01 (C)","question":"What is the most common use of the “reverse split” function of a VHF/UHF transceiver?","A":"A. Reduce power output","B":"B. Increase power output","C":"C. Listen on a repeater’s input frequency","D":"D. Listen on a repeater’s output frequency"},{"answer":"T2B02 (D)","question":"What term describes the use of a sub-audible tone transmitted along with normal voice audio to open the squelch of a receiver?","A":"A. Carrier squelch","B":"B. Tone burst","C":"C. DTMF","D":"D. CTCSS"},{"answer":"T2B03 (B)","question":"If a station is not strong enough to keep a repeater’s receiver squelch open, which of the following might allow you to receive the station’s signal?","A":"A. Open the squelch on your radio","B":"B. Listen on the repeater input frequency","C":"C. Listen on the repeater output frequency","D":"D. Increase your transmit power"},{"answer":"T2B04 (D)","question":"Which of the following could be the reason you are unable to access a repeater whose output you can hear?","A":"A. Improper transceiver offset","B":"B. The repeater may require a proper CTCSS tone from your transceiver","C":"C. The repeater may require a proper DCS tone from your transceiver","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T2B05 (C)","question":"What might be the problem if a repeater user says your transmissions are breaking up on voice peaks?","A":"A. You have the incorrect offset","B":"B. You need to talk louder","C":"C. You are talking too loudly","D":"D. Your transmit power is too high"},{"answer":"T2B06 (A)","question":"What type of tones are used to control repeaters linked by the Internet Relay Linking Project (IRLP) protocol?","A":"A. DTMF","B":"B. CTCSS","C":"C. EchoLink","D":"D. Sub-audible"},{"answer":"T2B07 (C)","question":"How can you join a digital repeater’s “talk group”?","A":"A. Register your radio with the local FCC office","B":"B. Join the repeater owner’s club","C":"C. Program your radio with the group’s ID or code","D":"D. Sign your call after the courtesy tone"},{"answer":"T2B08 (A)","question":"Which of the following applies when two stations transmitting on the same frequency interfere with each other?","A":"A. Common courtesy should prevail, but no one has absolute right to an amateur frequency","B":"B. Whoever has the strongest signal has priority on the frequency","C":"C. Whoever has been on the frequency the longest has priority on the frequency","D":"D. The station that has the weakest signal has priority on the frequency"},{"answer":"T2B09 (B)","question":"What is a “talk group” on a DMR digital repeater?","A":"A. A group of operators sharing common interests","B":"B. A way for groups of users to share a channel at different times without being heard by other users on the channel","C":"C. A protocol that increases the signal-to-noise ratio when multiple repeaters are linked together","D":"D. A net that meets at a particular time"},{"answer":"T2B10 (A)","question":"Which Q signal indicates that you are receiving interference from other stations?","A":"A. QRM","B":"B. QRN","C":"C. QTH","D":"D. QSB"},{"answer":"T2B11 (B)","question":"Which Q signal indicates that you are changing frequency?","A":"A. QRU","B":"B. QSY","C":"C. QSL","D":"D. QRZ"},{"answer":"T2B12 (A)","question":"Why are simplex channels designated in the VHF/UHF band plans?","A":"A. So that stations within mutual communications range can communicate without tying up a repeater","B":"B. For contest operation","C":"C. For working DX only","D":"D. So that stations with simple transmitters can access the repeater without automated offset"},{"answer":"T2B13 (C)","question":"Where may SSB phone be used in amateur bands above 50 MHz?","A":"A. Only in sub-bands allocated to General class or higher licensees","B":"B. Only on repeaters","C":"C. In at least some portion of all these bands","D":"D. On any band as long as power is limited to 25 watts"},{"answer":"T2B14 (A)","question":"Which of the following describes a linked repeater network?","A":"A. A network of repeaters where signals received by one repeater are repeated by all the repeaters","B":"B. A repeater with more than one receiver","C":"C. Multiple repeaters with the same owner","D":"D. A system of repeaters linked by APRS"}]},"T2C":{"section_name":"T2C - Public service: emergency and non-emergency operations; applicability of FCC rules; RACES and ARES; net and traffic procedures; operating restrictions during emergencies","questions":[{"answer":"T2C01 (D) [97.103(a)]","question":"When do the FCC rules NOT apply to the operation of an amateur station?","A":"A. When operating a RACES station","B":"B. When operating under special FEMA rules","C":"C. When operating under special ARES rules","D":"D. Never, FCC rules always apply"},{"answer":"T2C02 (B)","question":"What is meant by the term \\"NCS\\" used in net operation?","A":"A. Nominal Control System","B":"B. Net Control Station","C":"C. National Communications Standard","D":"D. Normal Communications Syntax"},{"answer":"T2C03 (C)","question":"What should be done when using voice modes to ensure that voice messages containing unusual words are received correctly?","A":"A. Send the words by voice and Morse code","B":"B. Speak very loudly into the microphone","C":"C. Spell the words using a standard phonetic alphabet","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T2C04 (D)","question":"What do RACES and ARES have in common?","A":"A. They represent the two largest ham clubs in the United States","B":"B. Both organizations broadcast road and weather information","C":"C. Neither may handle emergency traffic supporting public service agencies","D":"D. Both organizations may provide communications during emergencies"},{"answer":"T2C05 (A)","question":"What does the term “traffic” refer to in net operation?","A":"A. Formal messages exchanged by net stations","B":"B. The number of stations checking in and out of a net","C":"C. Operation by mobile or portable stations","D":"D. Requests to activate the net by a served agency"},{"answer":"T2C06 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an accepted practice to get the immediate attention of a net control station when reporting an emergency?","A":"A. Repeat \\"SOS\\" three times followed by the call sign of the reporting station","B":"B. Press the push-to-talk button three times","C":"C. Begin your transmission by saying \\"Priority\\" or \\"Emergency\\" followed by your call sign","D":"D. Play a pre-recorded emergency alert tone followed by your call sign"},{"answer":"T2C07 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an accepted practice for an amateur operator who has checked into a net?","A":"A. Provided that the frequency is quiet, announce the station call sign and location every 5 minutes","B":"B. Move 5 kHz away from the net\'s frequency and use high power to ask other hams to keep clear of the net frequency","C":"C. Remain on frequency without transmitting until asked to do so by the net control station","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T2C08 (A)","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of good traffic handling?","A":"A. Passing messages exactly as received","B":"B. Making decisions as to whether messages are worthy of relay or delivery","C":"C. Ensuring that any newsworthy messages are relayed to the news media","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T2C09 (D)","question":"Are amateur station control operators ever permitted to operate outside the frequency privileges of their license class?","A":"A. No","B":"B. Yes, but only when part of a FEMA emergency plan","C":"C. Yes, but only when part of a RACES emergency plan","D":"D. Yes, but only if necessary in situations involving the immediate safety of human life or protection of property"},{"answer":"T2C10 (D)","question":"What information is contained in the preamble of a formal traffic message?","A":"A. The email address of the originating station","B":"B. The address of the intended recipient","C":"C. The telephone number of the addressee","D":"D. The information needed to track the message"},{"answer":"T2C11 (A)","question":"What is meant by the term “check,” in reference to a formal traffic message?","A":"A. The number of words or word equivalents in the text portion of the message","B":"B. The value of a money order attached to the message","C":"C. A list of stations that have relayed the message","D":"D. A box on the message form that indicates that the message was received and/or relayed"},{"answer":"T2C12 (A)","question":"What is the Amateur Radio Emergency Service (ARES)?","A":"A. Licensed amateurs who have voluntarily registered their qualifications and equipment for communications duty in the public service","B":"B. Licensed amateurs who are members of the military and who voluntarily agreed to provide message handling services in the case of an emergency","C":"C. A training program that provides licensing courses for those interested in obtaining an amateur license to use during emergencies","D":"D. A training program that certifies amateur operators for membership in the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T3":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T3 - Radio wave characteristics: properties of radio waves; propagation modes - [3 Exam Questions - 3 Groups]","section_groups":["T3A","T3B","T3C"],"T3A":{"name":"T3A - Radio wave characteristics: how a radio signal travels; fading; multipath; polarization; wavelength vs absorption; antenna orientation","questions":[{"answer":"T3A01 (D)","question":"What should you do if another operator reports that your station’s 2 meter signals were strong just a moment ago, but now they are weak or distorted?","A":"A. Change the batteries in your radio to a different type","B":"B. Turn on the CTCSS tone","C":"C. Ask the other operator to adjust his squelch control","D":"D. Try moving a few feet or changing the direction of your antenna if possible, as reflections may be causing multi-path distortion"},{"answer":"T3A02 (B)","question":"Why might the range of VHF and UHF signals be greater in the winter?","A":"A. Less ionospheric absorption","B":"B. Less absorption by vegetation","C":"C. Less solar activity","D":"D. Less tropospheric absorption"},{"answer":"T3A03 (C)","question":"What antenna polarization is normally used for long-distance weak-signal CW and SSB contacts using the VHF and UHF bands?","A":"A. Right-hand circular","B":"B. Left-hand circular","C":"C. Horizontal","D":"D. Vertical"},{"answer":"T3A04 (B)","question":"What can happen if the antennas at opposite ends of a VHF or UHF line of sight radio link are not using the same polarization?","A":"A. The modulation sidebands might become inverted","B":"B. Signals could be significantly weaker","C":"C. Signals have an echo effect on voices","D":"D. Nothing significant will happen"},{"answer":"T3A05 (B)","question":"When using a directional antenna, how might your station be able to access a distant repeater if buildings or obstructions are blocking the direct line of sight path?","A":"A. Change from vertical to horizontal polarization","B":"B. Try to find a path that reflects signals to the repeater","C":"C. Try the long path","D":"D. Increase the antenna SWR"},{"answer":"T3A06 (B)","question":"What term is commonly used to describe the rapid fluttering sound sometimes heard from mobile stations that are moving while transmitting?","A":"A. Flip-flopping","B":"B. Picket fencing","C":"C. Frequency shifting","D":"D. Pulsing"},{"answer":"T3A07 (A)","question":"What type of wave carries radio signals between transmitting and receiving stations?","A":"A. Electromagnetic","B":"B. Electrostatic","C":"C. Surface acoustic","D":"D. Ferromagnetic"},{"answer":"T3A08 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a likely cause of irregular fading of signals received by ionospheric reflection?","A":"A. Frequency shift due to Faraday rotation","B":"B. Interference from thunderstorms","C":"C. Random combining of signals arriving via different paths","D":"D. Intermodulation distortion"},{"answer":"T3A09 (B)","question":"Which of the following results from the fact that skip signals refracted from the ionosphere are elliptically polarized?","A":"A. Digital modes are unusable","B":"B. Either vertically or horizontally polarized antennas may be used for transmission or reception","C":"C. FM voice is unusable","D":"D. Both the transmitting and receiving antennas must be of the same polarization"},{"answer":"T3A10 (D)","question":"What may occur if data signals arrive via multiple paths?","A":"A. Transmission rates can be increased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed","B":"B. Transmission rates must be decreased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed","C":"C. No significant changes will occur if the signals are transmitted using FM","D":"D. Error rates are likely to increase"},{"answer":"T3A11 (C)","question":"Which part of the atmosphere enables the propagation of radio signals around the world?","A":"A. The stratosphere","B":"B. The troposphere","C":"C. The ionosphere","D":"D. The magnetosphere"},{"answer":"T3A12 (B)","question":"How might fog and light rain affect radio range on the 10 meter and 6 meter bands?","A":"A. Fog and rain absorb these wavelength bands","B":"B. Fog and light rain will have little effect on these bands","C":"C. Fog and rain will deflect these signals","D":"D. Fog and rain will increase radio range"},{"answer":"T3A13 (C)","question":"What weather condition would decrease range at microwave frequencies?","A":"A. High winds","B":"B. Low barometric pressure","C":"C. Precipitation","D":"D. Colder temperatures"}]},"T3B":{"section_name":"T3B - Radio and electromagnetic wave properties: the electromagnetic spectrum; wavelength vs frequency; nature and velocity of electromagnetic waves; definition of UHF, VHF, HF bands; calculating wavelength","questions":[{"answer":"T3B01 (C)","question":"What is the name for the distance a radio wave travels during one complete cycle?","A":"A. Wave speed","B":"B. Waveform","C":"C. Wavelength","D":"D. Wave spread"},{"answer":"T3B02 (A)","question":"What property of a radio wave is used to describe its polarization?","A":"A. The orientation of the electric field","B":"B. The orientation of the magnetic field","C":"C. The ratio of the energy in the magnetic field to the energy in the electric field","D":"D. The ratio of the velocity to the wavelength"},{"answer":"T3B03 (C)","question":"What are the two components of a radio wave?","A":"A. AC and DC","B":"B. Voltage and current","C":"C. Electric and magnetic fields","D":"D. Ionizing and non-ionizing radiation"},{"answer":"T3B04 (A)","question":"How fast does a radio wave travel through free space?","A":"A. At the speed of light","B":"B. At the speed of sound","C":"C. Its speed is inversely proportional to its wavelength","D":"D. Its speed increases as the frequency increases"},{"answer":"T3B05 (B)","question":"How does the wavelength of a radio wave relate to its frequency?","A":"A. The wavelength gets longer as the frequency increases","B":"B. The wavelength gets shorter as the frequency increases","C":"C. There is no relationship between wavelength and frequency","D":"D. The wavelength depends on the bandwidth of the signal"},{"answer":"T3B06 (D)","question":"What is the formula for converting frequency to approximate wavelength in meters?","A":"A. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz multiplied by 300","B":"B. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz divided by 300","C":"C. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in megahertz divided by 300","D":"D. Wavelength in meters equals 300 divided by frequency in megahertz"},{"answer":"T3B07 (A)","question":"What property of radio waves is often used to identify the different frequency bands?","A":"A. The approximate wavelength","B":"B. The magnetic intensity of waves","C":"C. The time it takes for waves to travel one mile","D":"D. The voltage standing wave ratio of waves"},{"answer":"T3B08 (B)","question":"What are the frequency limits of the VHF spectrum?","A":"A. 30 to 300 kHz","B":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","C":"C. 300 to 3000 kHz","D":"D. 300 to 3000 MHz"},{"answer":"T3B09 (D)","question":"What are the frequency limits of the UHF spectrum?","A":"A. 30 to 300 kHz","B":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","C":"C. 300 to 3000 kHz","D":"D. 300 to 3000 MHz"},{"answer":"T3B10 (C)","question":"What frequency range is referred to as HF?","A":"A. 300 to 3000 MHz","B":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","C":"C. 3 to 30 MHz","D":"D. 300 to 3000 kHz"},{"answer":"T3B11 (B)","question":"What is the approximate velocity of a radio wave as it travels through free space?","A":"A. 150,000 kilometers per second","B":"B. 300,000,000 meters per second","C":"C. 300,000,000 miles per hour","D":"D. 150,000 miles per hour"}]},"T3C":{"section_name":"T3C - Propagation modes: line of sight; sporadic E; meteor and auroral scatter and reflections; tropospheric ducting; F layer skip; radio horizon","questions":[{"answer":"T3C01 (C)","question":"Why are direct (not via a repeater) UHF signals rarely heard from stations outside your local coverage area?","A":"A. They are too weak to go very far","B":"B. FCC regulations prohibit them from going more than 50 miles","C":"C. UHF signals are usually not reflected by the ionosphere","D":"D. UHF signals are absorbed by the ionospheric D layer"},{"answer":"T3C02 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an advantage of HF vs VHF and higher frequencies?","A":"A. HF antennas are generally smaller","B":"B. HF accommodates wider bandwidth signals","C":"C. Long distance ionospheric propagation is far more common on HF","D":"D. There is less atmospheric interference (static) on HF"},{"answer":"T3C03 (B)","question":"What is a characteristic of VHF signals received via auroral reflection?","A":"A. Signals from distances of 10,000 or more miles are common","B":"B. The signals exhibit rapid fluctuations of strength and often sound distorted","C":"C. These types of signals occur only during winter nighttime hours","D":"D. These types of signals are generally strongest when your antenna is aimed west"},{"answer":"T3C04 (B)","question":"Which of the following propagation types is most commonly associated with occasional strong over-the-horizon signals on the 10, 6, and 2 meter bands?","A":"A. Backscatter","B":"B. Sporadic E","C":"C. D layer absorption","D":"D. Gray-line propagation"},{"answer":"T3C05 (A)","question":"Which of the following effects might cause radio signals to be heard despite obstructions between the transmitting and receiving stations?","A":"A. Knife-edge diffraction","B":"B. Faraday rotation","C":"C. Quantum tunneling","D":"D. Doppler shift"},{"answer":"T3C06 (A)","question":"What mode is responsible for allowing over-the-horizon VHF and UHF communications to ranges of approximately 300 miles on a regular basis?","A":"A. Tropospheric ducting","B":"B. D layer refraction","C":"C. F2 layer refraction","D":"D. Faraday rotation"},{"answer":"T3C07 (B)","question":"What band is best suited for communicating via meteor scatter?","A":"A. 10 meter band","B":"B. 6 meter band","C":"C. 2 meter band","D":"D. 70 centimeter band"},{"answer":"T3C08 (D)","question":"What causes tropospheric ducting?","A":"A. Discharges of lightning during electrical storms","B":"B. Sunspots and solar flares","C":"C. Updrafts from hurricanes and tornadoes","D":"D. Temperature inversions in the atmosphere"},{"answer":"T3C09 (A)","question":"What is generally the best time for long-distance 10 meter band propagation via the F layer?","A":"A. From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of high sunspot activity","B":"B. From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of high sunspot activity","C":"C. From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of low sunspot activity","D":"D. From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of low sunspot activity"},{"answer":"T3C10 (A)","question":"Which of the following bands may provide long distance communications during the peak of the sunspot cycle?","A":"A. 6 or 10 meter bands","B":"B. 23 centimeter band","C":"C. 70 centimeter or 1.25 meter bands","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T3C11 (C)","question":"Why do VHF and UHF radio signals usually travel somewhat farther than the visual line of sight distance between two stations?","A":"A. Radio signals move somewhat faster than the speed of light","B":"B. Radio waves are not blocked by dust particles","C":"C. The Earth seems less curved to radio waves than to light","D":"D. Radio waves are blocked by dust particles"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T4":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T4 - Amateur radio practices and station set-up - [2 Exam Questions - 2 Groups]","section_groups":["T4A","T4B"],"T4A":{"name":"T4A - Station setup: connecting microphones; reducing unwanted emissions; power source; connecting a computer; RF grounding; connecting digital equipment; connecting an SWR meter","questions":[{"answer":"T4A01 (D)","question":"What must be considered to determine the minimum current capacity needed for a transceiver power supply?","A":"A. Efficiency of the transmitter at full power output","B":"B. Receiver and control circuit power","C":"C. Power supply regulation and heat dissipation","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4A02 (D)","question":"How might a computer be used as part of an amateur radio station?","A":"A. For logging contacts and contact information","B":"B. For sending and/or receiving CW","C":"C. For generating and decoding digital signals","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4A03 (A)","question":"Why should wiring between the power source and radio be heavy-gauge wire and kept as short as possible?","A":"A. To avoid voltage falling below that needed for proper operation","B":"B. To provide a good counterpoise for the antenna","C":"C. To avoid RF interference","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4A04 (C)","question":"Which computer sound card port is connected to a transceiver’s headphone or speaker output for operating digital modes?","A":"A. Headphone output","B":"B. Mute","C":"C. Microphone or line input","D":"D. PCI or SDI"},{"answer":"T4A05 (A)","question":"What is the proper location for an external SWR meter?","A":"A. In series with the feed line, between the transmitter and antenna","B":"B. In series with the station\'s ground","C":"C. In parallel with the push-to-talk line and the antenna","D":"D. In series with the power supply cable, as close as possible to the radio"},{"answer":"T4A06 (C)","question":"Which of the following connections might be used between a voice transceiver and a computer for digital operation?","A":"A. Receive and transmit mode, status, and location","B":"B. Antenna and RF power","C":"C. Receive audio, transmit audio, and push-to-talk (PTT)","D":"D. NMEA GPS location and DC power"},{"answer":"T4A07 (C)","question":"How is a computer’s sound card used when conducting digital communications?","A":"A. The sound card communicates between the computer CPU and the video display","B":"B. The sound card records the audio frequency for video display","C":"C. The sound card provides audio to the radio\'s microphone input and converts received audio to digital form","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4A08 (D)","question":"Which of the following conductors provides the lowest impedance to RF signals?","A":"A. Round stranded wire","B":"B. Round copper-clad steel wire","C":"C. Twisted-pair cable","D":"D. Flat strap"},{"answer":"T4A09 (D)","question":"Which of the following could you use to cure distorted audio caused by RF current on the shield of a microphone cable?","A":"A. Band-pass filter","B":"B. Low-pass filter","C":"C. Preamplifier","D":"D. Ferrite choke"},{"answer":"T4A10 (B)","question":"What is the source of a high-pitched whine that varies with engine speed in a mobile transceiver’s receive audio?","A":"A. The ignition system","B":"B. The alternator","C":"C. The electric fuel pump","D":"D. Anti-lock braking system controllers"},{"answer":"T4A11 (A)","question":"Where should the negative return connection of a mobile transceiver\'s power cable be connected?","A":"A. At the battery or engine block ground strap","B":"B. At the antenna mount","C":"C. To any metal part of the vehicle","D":"D. Through the transceiver’s mounting bracket"}]},"T4B":{"section_name":"T4B - Operating controls: tuning; use of filters; squelch function; AGC; transceiver operation; memory channels","questions":[{"answer":"T4B01 (B)","question":"What may happen if a transmitter is operated with the microphone gain set too high?","A":"A. The output power might be too high","B":"B. The output signal might become distorted","C":"C. The frequency might vary","D":"D. The SWR might increase"},{"answer":"T4B02 (A)","question":"Which of the following can be used to enter the operating frequency on a modern transceiver?","A":"A. The keypad or VFO knob","B":"B. The CTCSS or DTMF encoder","C":"C. The Automatic Frequency Control","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4B03 (D)","question":"What is the purpose of the squelch control on a transceiver?","A":"A. To set the highest level of volume desired","B":"B. To set the transmitter power level","C":"C. To adjust the automatic gain control","D":"D. To mute receiver output noise when no signal is being received"},{"answer":"T4B04 (B)","question":"What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency on your transceiver?","A":"A. Enable the CTCSS tones","B":"B. Store the frequency in a memory channel","C":"C. Disable the CTCSS tones","D":"D. Use the scan mode to select the desired frequency"},{"answer":"T4B05 (C)","question":"Which of the following would reduce ignition interference to a receiver?","A":"A. Change frequency slightly","B":"B. Decrease the squelch setting","C":"C. Turn on the noise blanker","D":"D. Use the RIT control"},{"answer":"T4B06 (D)","question":"Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal seems too high or low?","A":"A. The AGC or limiter","B":"B. The bandwidth selection","C":"C. The tone squelch","D":"D. The receiver RIT or clarifier"},{"answer":"T4B07 (B)","question":"What does the term “RIT” mean?","A":"A. Receiver Input Tone","B":"B. Receiver Incremental Tuning","C":"C. Rectifier Inverter Test","D":"D. Remote Input Transmitter"},{"answer":"T4B08 (B)","question":"What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?","A":"A. Permits monitoring several modes at once","B":"B. Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode","C":"C. Increases the number of frequencies that can be stored in memory","D":"D. Increases the amount of offset between receive and transmit frequencies"},{"answer":"T4B09 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth for minimizing noise and interference for SSB reception?","A":"A. 500 Hz","B":"B. 1000 Hz","C":"C. 2400 Hz","D":"D. 5000 Hz"},{"answer":"T4B10 (A)","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth for minimizing noise and interference for CW reception?","A":"A. 500 Hz","B":"B. 1000 Hz","C":"C. 2400 Hz","D":"D. 5000 Hz"},{"answer":"T4B11 (A)","question":"What is the function of automatic gain control, or AGC?","A":"A. To keep received audio relatively constant","B":"B. To protect an antenna from lightning","C":"C. To eliminate RF on the station cabling","D":"D. An asymmetric goniometer control used for antenna matching"},{"answer":"T4B12 (B)","question":"Which of the following could be used to remove power line noise or ignition noise?","A":"A. Squelch","B":"B. Noise blanker","C":"C. Notch filter","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T4B13 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a use for the scanning function of an FM transceiver?","A":"A. To check incoming signal deviation","B":"B. To prevent interference to nearby repeaters","C":"C. To scan through a range of frequencies to check for activity","D":"D. To check for messages left on a digital bulletin board"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T5":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T5 - Electrical principles: math for electronics; electronic principles; Ohm’s Law - [4 Exam Questions - 4 Groups]","section_groups":["T5A","T5B","T5C","T5D"],"T5A":{"name":"T5A - Electrical principles, units, and terms: current and voltage; conductors and insulators; alternating and direct current; series and parallel circuits","questions":[{"answer":"T5A01 (D)","question":"Electrical current is measured in which of the following units?","A":"A. Volts","B":"B. Watts","C":"C. Ohms","D":"D. Amperes"},{"answer":"T5A02 (B)","question":"Electrical power is measured in which of the following units?","A":"A. Volts","B":"B. Watts","C":"C. Ohms","D":"D. Amperes"},{"answer":"T5A03 (D)","question":"What is the name for the flow of electrons in an electric circuit?","A":"A. Voltage","B":"B. Resistance","C":"C. Capacitance","D":"D. Current"},{"answer":"T5A06 (A)","question":"How much voltage does a mobile transceiver typically require?","A":"A. About 12 volts","B":"B. About 30 volts","C":"C. About 120 volts","D":"D. About 240 volts"},{"answer":"T5A07 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a good electrical conductor?","A":"A. Glass","B":"B. Wood","C":"C. Copper","D":"D. Rubber"},{"answer":"T5A08 (B)","question":"Which of the following is a good electrical insulator?","A":"A. Copper","B":"B. Glass","C":"C. Aluminum","D":"D. Mercury"},{"answer":"T5A09 (A)","question":"What is the name for a current that reverses direction on a regular basis?","A":"A. Alternating current","B":"B. Direct current","C":"C. Circular current","D":"D. Vertical current"},{"answer":"T5A10 (C)","question":"Which term describes the rate at which electrical energy is used?","A":"A. Resistance","B":"B. Current","C":"C. Power","D":"D. Voltage"},{"answer":"T5A11 (A)","question":"What is the unit of electromotive force?","A":"A. The volt","B":"B. The watt","C":"C. The ampere","D":"D. The ohm"},{"answer":"T5A12 (D)","question":"What describes the number of times per second that an alternating current makes a complete cycle?","A":"A. Pulse rate","B":"B. Speed","C":"C. Wavelength","D":"D. Frequency"},{"answer":"T5A13 (A)","question":"In which type of circuit is current the same through all components?","A":"A. Series","B":"B. Parallel","C":"C. Resonant","D":"D. Branch"},{"answer":"T5A14 (B)","question":"In which type of circuit is voltage the same across all components?","A":"A. Series","B":"B. Parallel","C":"C. Resonant","D":"D. Branch"}]},"T5B":{"section_name":"T5B - Math for electronics: conversion of electrical units; decibels; the metric system","questions":[{"answer":"T5B01 (C)","question":"How many milliamperes is 1.5 amperes?","A":"A. 15 milliamperes","B":"B. 150 milliamperes","C":"C. 1500 milliamperes","D":"D. 15,000 milliamperes"},{"answer":"T5B02 (A)","question":"What is another way to specify a radio signal frequency of 1,500,000 hertz?","A":"A. 1500 kHz","B":"B. 1500 MHz","C":"C. 15 GHz","D":"D. 150 kHz"},{"answer":"T5B03 (C)","question":"How many volts are equal to one kilovolt?","A":"A. One one-thousandth of a volt","B":"B. One hundred volts","C":"C. One thousand volts","D":"D. One million volts"},{"answer":"T5B04 (A)","question":"How many volts are equal to one microvolt?","A":"A. One one-millionth of a volt","B":"B. One million volts","C":"C. One thousand kilovolts","D":"D. One one-thousandth of a volt"},{"answer":"T5B05 (B)","question":"Which of the following is equal to 500 milliwatts?","A":"A. 0.02 watts","B":"B. 0.5 watts","C":"C. 5 watts","D":"D. 50 watts"},{"answer":"T5B06 (C)","question":"If an ammeter calibrated in amperes is used to measure a 3000-milliampere current, what reading would it show?","A":"A. 0.003 amperes","B":"B. 0.3 amperes","C":"C. 3 amperes","D":"D. 3,000,000 amperes"},{"answer":"T5B07 (C)","question":"If a frequency display calibrated in megahertz shows a reading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show if it were calibrated in kilohertz?","A":"A. 0.003525 kHz","B":"B. 35.25 kHz","C":"C. 3525 kHz","D":"D. 3,525,000 kHz"},{"answer":"T5B08 (B)","question":"How many microfarads are equal to 1,000,000 picofarads?","A":"A. 0.001 microfarads","B":"B. 1 microfarad","C":"C. 1000 microfarads","D":"D. 1,000,000,000 microfarads"},{"answer":"T5B09 (B)","question":"What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 5 watts to 10 watts?","A":"A. 2 dB","B":"B. 3 dB","C":"C. 5 dB","D":"D. 10 dB"},{"answer":"T5B10 (C)","question":"What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power decrease from 12 watts to 3 watts?","A":"A. -1 dB","B":"B. -3 dB","C":"C. -6 dB","D":"D. -9 dB"},{"answer":"T5B11 (A)","question":"What is the amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 20 watts to 200 watts?","A":"A. 10 dB","B":"B. 12 dB","C":"C. 18 dB","D":"D. 28 dB"},{"answer":"T5B12 (A)","question":"Which of the following frequencies is equal to 28,400 kHz?","A":"A. 28.400 MHz","B":"B. 2.800 MHz","C":"C. 284.00 MHz","D":"D. 28.400 kHz"},{"answer":"T5B13 (C)","question":"If a frequency display shows a reading of 2425 MHz, what frequency is that in GHz?","A":"A. 0.002425 GHz","B":"B. 24.25 GHz","C":"C. 2.425 GHz","D":"D. 2425 GHz"}]},"T5C":{"section_name":"T5C - Electronic principles: capacitance; inductance; current flow in circuits; alternating current; definition of RF; definition of polarity; DC power calculations; impedance","questions":[{"answer":"T5C01 (D)","question":"What is the ability to store energy in an electric field called?","A":"A. Inductance","B":"B. Resistance","C":"C. Tolerance","D":"D. Capacitance"},{"answer":"T5C02 (A)","question":"What is the basic unit of capacitance?","A":"A. The farad","B":"B. The ohm","C":"C. The volt","D":"D. The henry"},{"answer":"T5C03 (D)","question":"What is the ability to store energy in a magnetic field called?","A":"A. Admittance","B":"B. Capacitance","C":"C. Resistance","D":"D. Inductance"},{"answer":"T5C04 (C)","question":"What is the basic unit of inductance?","A":"A. The coulomb","B":"B. The farad","C":"C. The henry","D":"D. The ohm"},{"answer":"T5C05 (A)","question":"What is the unit of frequency?","A":"A. Hertz","B":"B. Henry","C":"C. Farad","D":"D. Tesla"},{"answer":"T5C06 (A)","question":"What does the abbreviation “RF” refer to?","A":"A. Radio frequency signals of all types","B":"B. The resonant frequency of a tuned circuit","C":"C. The real frequency transmitted as opposed to the apparent frequency","D":"D. Reflective force in antenna transmission lines"},{"answer":"T5C07 (B)","question":"A radio wave is made up of what type of energy?","A":"A. Pressure","B":"B. Electromagnetic","C":"C. Gravity","D":"D. Thermal"},{"answer":"T5C08 (A)","question":"What is the formula used to calculate electrical power in a DC circuit?","A":"A. Power (P) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)","B":"B. Power (P) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)","C":"C. Power (P) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)","D":"D. Power (P) equals voltage (E) plus current (I)"},{"answer":"T5C09 (A)","question":"How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 13.8 volts DC and the current is 10 amperes?","A":"A. 138 watts","B":"B. 0.7 watts","C":"C. 23.8 watts","D":"D. 3.8 watts"},{"answer":"T5C10 (B)","question":"How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the current is 2.5 amperes?","A":"A. 4.8 watts","B":"B. 30 watts","C":"C. 14.5 watts","D":"D. 0.208 watts"},{"answer":"T5C11 (B)","question":"How many amperes are flowing in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the load is 120 watts?","A":"A. 0.1 amperes","B":"B. 10 amperes","C":"C. 12 amperes","D":"D. 132 amperes"},{"answer":"T5C12 (A)","question":"What is impedance?","A":"A. A measure of the opposition to AC current flow in a circuit","B":"B. The inverse of resistance","C":"C. The Q or Quality Factor of a component","D":"D. The power handling capability of a component"},{"answer":"T5C13 (D)","question":"What is a unit of impedance?","A":"A. Volts","B":"B. Amperes","C":"C. Coulombs","D":"D. Ohms"},{"answer":"T5C14 (D)","question":"What is the proper abbreviation for megahertz?","A":"A. mHz","B":"B. mhZ","C":"C. Mhz","D":"D. MHz"}]},"T5D":{"section_name":"T5D - Ohm’s Law: formulas and usage; components in series and parallel","questions":[{"answer":"T5D01 (B)","question":"What formula is used to calculate current in a circuit?","A":"A. Current (I) equals voltage (E) multiplied by resistance (R)","B":"B. Current (I) equals voltage (E) divided by resistance (R)","C":"C. Current (I) equals voltage (E) added to resistance (R)","D":"D. Current (I) equals voltage (E) minus resistance (R)"},{"answer":"T5D02 (A)","question":"What formula is used to calculate voltage in a circuit?","A":"A. Voltage (E) equals current (I) multiplied by resistance (R)","B":"B. Voltage (E) equals current (I) divided by resistance (R)","C":"C. Voltage (E) equals current (I) added to resistance (R)","D":"D. Voltage (E) equals current (I) minus resistance (R)"},{"answer":"T5D03 (B)","question":"What formula is used to calculate resistance in a circuit?","A":"A. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)","B":"B. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)","C":"C. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) added to current (I)","D":"D. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)"},{"answer":"T5D04 (B)","question":"What is the resistance of a circuit in which a current of 3 amperes flows through a resistor connected to 90 volts?","A":"A. 3 ohms","B":"B. 30 ohms","C":"C. 93 ohms","D":"D. 270 ohms"},{"answer":"T5D05 (C)","question":"What is the resistance in a circuit for which the applied voltage is 12 volts and the current flow is 1.5 amperes?","A":"A. 18 ohms","B":"B. 0.125 ohms","C":"C. 8 ohms","D":"D. 13.5 ohms"},{"answer":"T5D06 (A)","question":"What is the resistance of a circuit that draws 4 amperes from a 12-volt source?","A":"A. 3 ohms","B":"B. 16 ohms","C":"C. 48 ohms","D":"D. 8 ohms"},{"answer":"T5D07 (D)","question":"What is the current in a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a resistance of 80 ohms?","A":"A. 9600 amperes","B":"B. 200 amperes","C":"C. 0.667 amperes","D":"D. 1.5 amperes"},{"answer":"T5D08 (C)","question":"What is the current through a 100-ohm resistor connected across 200 volts?","A":"A. 20,000 amperes","B":"B. 0.5 amperes","C":"C. 2 amperes","D":"D. 100 amperes"},{"answer":"T5D09 (C)","question":"What is the current through a 24-ohm resistor connected across 240 volts?","A":"A. 24,000 amperes","B":"B. 0.1 amperes","C":"C. 10 amperes","D":"D. 216 amperes"},{"answer":"T5D10 (A)","question":"What is the voltage across a 2-ohm resistor if a current of 0.5 amperes flows through it?","A":"A. 1 volt","B":"B. 0.25 volts","C":"C. 2.5 volts","D":"D. 1.5 volts"},{"answer":"T5D11 (B)","question":"What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 1 ampere flows through it?","A":"A. 1 volt","B":"B. 10 volts","C":"C. 11 volts","D":"D. 9 volts"},{"answer":"T5D12 (D)","question":"What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 2 amperes flows through it?","A":"A. 8 volts","B":"B. 0.2 volts","C":"C. 12 volts","D":"D. 20 volts"},{"answer":"T5D13 (B)","question":"What happens to current at the junction of two components in series?","A":"A. It divides equally between them","B":"B. It is unchanged","C":"C. It divides based on the on the value of the components","D":"D. The current in the second component is zero"},{"answer":"T5D14 (A)","question":"What happens to current at the junction of two components in parallel?","A":"A. It divides between them dependent on the value of the components","B":"B. It is the same in both components","C":"C. Its value doubles","D":"D. Its value is halved"},{"answer":"T5D15 (C)","question":"What is the voltage across each of two components in series with a voltage source?","A":"A. The same voltage as the source","B":"B. Half the source voltage","C":"C. It is determined by the type and value of the components","D":"D. Twice the source voltage"},{"answer":"T5D16 (D)","question":"What is the voltage across each of two components in parallel with a voltage source?","A":"A. It is determined by the type and value of the components","B":"B. Half the source voltage","C":"C. Twice the source voltage","D":"D. The same voltage as the source"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T6":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T6 - Electrical components; circuit diagrams; component functions - [4 Exam Questions - 4 Groups]","section_groups":["T6A","T6B","T6C","T6D"],"T6A":{"name":"T6A - Electrical components: fixed and variable resistors; capacitors and inductors; fuses; switches; batteries","questions":[{"answer":"T6A01 (B)","question":"What electrical component opposes the flow of current in a DC circuit?","A":"A. Inductor","B":"B. Resistor","C":"C. Voltmeter","D":"D. Transformer"},{"answer":"T6A02 (C)","question":"What type of component is often used as an adjustable volume control?","A":"A. Fixed resistor","B":"B. Power resistor","C":"C. Potentiometer","D":"D. Transformer"},{"answer":"T6A03 (B)","question":"What electrical parameter is controlled by a potentiometer?","A":"A. Inductance","B":"B. Resistance","C":"C. Capacitance","D":"D. Field strength"},{"answer":"T6A04 (B)","question":"What electrical component stores energy in an electric field?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Capacitor","C":"C. Inductor","D":"D. Diode"},{"answer":"T6A05 (D)","question":"What type of electrical component consists of two or more conductive surfaces separated by an insulator?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Potentiometer","C":"C. Oscillator","D":"D. Capacitor"},{"answer":"T6A06 (C)","question":"What type of electrical component stores energy in a magnetic field?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Capacitor","C":"C. Inductor","D":"D. Diode"},{"answer":"T6A07 (D)","question":"What electrical component usually is constructed as a coil of wire?","A":"A. Switch","B":"B. Capacitor","C":"C. Diode","D":"D. Inductor"},{"answer":"T6A08 (B)","question":"What electrical component is used to connect or disconnect electrical circuits?","A":"A. Magnetron","B":"B. Switch","C":"C. Thermistor","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T6A09 (A)","question":"What electrical component is used to protect other circuit components from current overloads?","A":"A. Fuse","B":"B. Capacitor","C":"C. Inductor","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T6A10 (D)","question":"Which of the following battery types is rechargeable?","A":"A. Nickel-metal hydride","B":"B. Lithium-ion","C":"C. Lead-acid gel-cell","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T6A11 (B)","question":"Which of the following battery types is not rechargeable?","A":"A. Nickel-cadmium","B":"B. Carbon-zinc","C":"C. Lead-acid","D":"D. Lithium-ion"}]},"T6B":{"section_name":"T6B - Semiconductors: basic principles and applications of solid state devices; diodes and transistors","questions":[{"answer":"T6B01 (D)","question":"What class of electronic components uses a voltage or current signal to control current flow?","A":"A. Capacitors","B":"B. Inductors","C":"C. Resistors","D":"D. Transistors"},{"answer":"T6B02 (C)","question":"What electronic component allows current to flow in only one direction?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Fuse","C":"C. Diode","D":"D. Driven element"},{"answer":"T6B03 (C)","question":"Which of these components can be used as an electronic switch or amplifier?","A":"A. Oscillator","B":"B. Potentiometer","C":"C. Transistor","D":"D. Voltmeter"},{"answer":"T6B04 (B)","question":"Which of the following components can consist of three layers of semiconductor material?","A":"A. Alternator","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Triode","D":"D. Pentagrid converter"},{"answer":"T6B05 (A)","question":"Which of the following electronic components can amplify signals?","A":"A. Transistor","B":"B. Variable resistor","C":"C. Electrolytic capacitor","D":"D. Multi-cell battery"},{"answer":"T6B06 (B)","question":"How is the cathode lead of a semiconductor diode often marked on the package?","A":"A. With the word \\"cathode\\"","B":"B. With a stripe","C":"C. With the letter C","D":"D. With the letter K"},{"answer":"T6B07 (B)","question":"What does the abbreviation LED stand for?","A":"A. Low Emission Diode","B":"B. Light Emitting Diode","C":"C. Liquid Emission Detector","D":"D. Long Echo Delay"},{"answer":"T6B08 (A)","question":"What does the abbreviation FET stand for?","A":"A. Field Effect Transistor","B":"B. Fast Electron Transistor","C":"C. Free Electron Transmitter","D":"D. Frequency Emission Transmitter"},{"answer":"T6B09 (C)","question":"What are the names of the two electrodes of a diode?","A":"A. Plus and minus","B":"B. Source and drain","C":"C. Anode and cathode","D":"D. Gate and base"},{"answer":"T6B10 (B)","question":"Which of the following could be the primary gain-producing component in an RF power amplifier?","A":"A. Transformer","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Reactor","D":"D. Resistor"},{"answer":"T6B11 (A)","question":"What is the term that describes a device\'s ability to amplify a signal?","A":"A. Gain","B":"B. Forward resistance","C":"C. Forward voltage drop","D":"D. On resistance"}]},"T6C":{"section_name":"T6C - Circuit diagrams; schematic symbols","questions":[{"answer":"T6C01 (C)","question":"What is the name of an electrical wiring diagram that uses standard component symbols?","A":"A. Bill of materials","B":"B. Connector pinout","C":"C. Schematic","D":"D. Flow chart"},{"answer":"T6C02 (A)","question":"What is component 1 in figure T1?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Battery","D":"D. Connector"},{"answer":"T6C03 (B)","question":"What is component 2 in figure T1?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Indicator lamp","D":"D. Connector"},{"answer":"T6C04 (C)","question":"What is component 3 in figure T1?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Lamp","D":"D. Ground symbol"},{"answer":"T6C05 (C)","question":"What is component 4 in figure T1?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Battery","D":"D. Ground symbol"},{"answer":"T6C06 (B)","question":"What is component 6 in figure T2?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Capacitor","C":"C. Regulator IC","D":"D. Transistor"},{"answer":"T6C07 (D)","question":"What is component 8 in figure T2?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Inductor","C":"C. Regulator IC","D":"D. Light emitting diode"},{"answer":"T6C08 (C)","question":"What is component 9 in figure T2?","A":"A. Variable capacitor","B":"B. Variable inductor","C":"C. Variable resistor","D":"D. Variable transformer"},{"answer":"T6C09 (D)","question":"What is component 4 in figure T2?","A":"A. Variable inductor","B":"B. Double-pole switch","C":"C. Potentiometer","D":"D. Transformer"},{"answer":"T6C10 (D)","question":"What is component 3 in figure T3?","A":"A. Connector","B":"B. Meter","C":"C. Variable capacitor","D":"D. Variable inductor"},{"answer":"T6C11 (A)","question":"What is component 4 in figure T3?","A":"A. Antenna","B":"B. Transmitter","C":"C. Dummy load","D":"D. Ground"},{"answer":"T6C12 (A)","question":"What do the symbols on an electrical schematic represent?","A":"A. Electrical components","B":"B. Logic states","C":"C. Digital codes","D":"D. Traffic nodes"},{"answer":"T6C13 (C)","question":"Which of the following is accurately represented in electrical schematics?","A":"A. Wire lengths","B":"B. Physical appearance of components","C":"C. The way components are interconnected","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"}]},"T6D":{"section_name":"T6D - Component functions: rectification; switches; indicators; power supply components; resonant circuit; shielding; power transformers; integrated circuits","questions":[{"answer":"T6D01 (B)","question":"Which of the following devices or circuits changes an alternating current into a varying direct current signal?","A":"A. Transformer","B":"B. Rectifier","C":"C. Amplifier","D":"D. Reflector"},{"answer":"T6D02 (A)","question":"What is a relay?","A":"A. An electrically-controlled switch","B":"B. A current controlled amplifier","C":"C. An optical sensor","D":"D. A pass transistor"},{"answer":"T6D03 (A)","question":"What type of switch is represented by component 3 in figure T2?","A":"A. Single-pole single-throw","B":"B. Single-pole double-throw","C":"C. Double-pole single-throw","D":"D. Double-pole double-throw"},{"answer":"T6D04 (C)","question":"Which of the following displays an electrical quantity as a numeric value?","A":"A. Potentiometer","B":"B. Transistor","C":"C. Meter","D":"D. Relay"},{"answer":"T6D05 (A)","question":"What type of circuit controls the amount of voltage from a power supply?","A":"A. Regulator","B":"B. Oscillator","C":"C. Filter","D":"D. Phase inverter"},{"answer":"T6D06 (B)","question":"What component is commonly used to change 120V AC house current to a lower AC voltage for other uses?","A":"A. Variable capacitor","B":"B. Transformer","C":"C. Transistor","D":"D. Diode"},{"answer":"T6D07 (A)","question":"Which of the following is commonly used as a visual indicator?","A":"A. LED","B":"B. FET","C":"C. Zener diode","D":"D. Bipolar transistor"},{"answer":"T6D08 (D)","question":"Which of the following is combined with an inductor to make a tuned circuit?","A":"A. Resistor","B":"B. Zener diode","C":"C. Potentiometer","D":"D. Capacitor"},{"answer":"T6D09 (C)","question":"What is the name of a device that combines several semiconductors and other components into one package?","A":"A. Transducer","B":"B. Multi-pole relay","C":"C. Integrated circuit","D":"D. Transformer"},{"answer":"T6D10 (C)","question":"What is the function of component 2 in Figure T1?","A":"A. Give off light when current flows through it","B":"B. Supply electrical energy","C":"C. Control the flow of current","D":"D. Convert electrical energy into radio waves"},{"answer":"T6D11 (A)","question":"Which of the following is a resonant or tuned circuit?","A":"A. An inductor and a capacitor connected in series or parallel to form a filter","B":"B. A type of voltage regulator","C":"C. A resistor circuit used for reducing standing wave ratio","D":"D. A circuit designed to provide high-fidelity audio"},{"answer":"T6D12 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a common reason to use shielded wire?","A":"A. To decrease the resistance of DC power connections","B":"B. To increase the current carrying capability of the wire","C":"C. To prevent coupling of unwanted signals to or from the wire","D":"D. To couple the wire to other signals"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T7":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T7 - Station equipment: common transmitter and receiver problems; antenna measurements; troubleshooting; basic repair and testing - [4 Exam Questions - 4 Groups]","section_groups":["T7A","T7B","T7C","T7D"],"T7A":{"name":"T7A - Station equipment: receivers; transmitters; transceivers; modulation; transverters; transmit and receive amplifiers","questions":[{"answer":"T7A01 (B)","question":"Which term describes the ability of a receiver to detect the presence of a signal?","A":"A. Linearity","B":"B. Sensitivity","C":"C. Selectivity","D":"D. Total Harmonic Distortion"},{"answer":"T7A02 (B)","question":"What is a transceiver?","A":"A. A type of antenna switch","B":"B. A unit combining the functions of a transmitter and a receiver","C":"C. A component in a repeater that filters out unwanted interference","D":"D. A type of antenna matching network"},{"answer":"T7A03 (B)","question":"Which of the following is used to convert a radio signal from one frequency to another?","A":"A. Phase splitter","B":"B. Mixer","C":"C. Inverter","D":"D. Amplifier"},{"answer":"T7A04 (C)","question":"Which term describes the ability of a receiver to discriminate between multiple signals?","A":"A. Discrimination ratio","B":"B. Sensitivity","C":"C. Selectivity","D":"D. Harmonic distortion"},{"answer":"T7A05 (D)","question":"What is the name of a circuit that generates a signal at a specific frequency?","A":"A. Reactance modulator","B":"B. Product detector","C":"C. Low-pass filter","D":"D. Oscillator"},{"answer":"T7A06 (C)","question":"What device converts the RF input and output of a transceiver to another band?","A":"A. High-pass filter","B":"B. Low-pass filter","C":"C. Transverter","D":"D. Phase converter"},{"answer":"T7A07 (D)","question":"What is meant by “PTT”?","A":"A. Pre-transmission tuning to reduce transmitter harmonic emission","B":"B. Precise tone transmissions used to limit repeater access to only certain signals","C":"C. A primary transformer tuner use to match antennas","D":"D. The push-to-talk function that switches between receive and transmit"},{"answer":"T7A08 (C)","question":"Which of the following describes combining speech with an RF carrier signal?","A":"A. Impedance matching","B":"B. Oscillation","C":"C. Modulation","D":"D. Low-pass filtering"},{"answer":"T7A09 (B)","question":"What is the function of the SSB/CW-FM switch on a VHF power amplifier?","A":"A. Change the mode of the transmitted signal","B":"B. Set the amplifier for proper operation in the selected mode","C":"C. Change the frequency range of the amplifier to operate in the proper portion of the band","D":"D. Reduce the received signal noise"},{"answer":"T7A10 (B)","question":"What device increases the low-power output from a handheld transceiver?","A":"A. A voltage divider","B":"B. An RF power amplifier","C":"C. An impedance network","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T7A11 (A)","question":"Where is an RF preamplifier installed?","A":"A. Between the antenna and receiver","B":"B. At the output of the transmitter\'s power amplifier","C":"C. Between a transmitter and antenna tuner","D":"D. At the receiver\'s audio output"}]},"T7B":{"section_name":"T7B - Common transmitter and receiver problems: symptoms of overload and overdrive; distortion; causes of interference; interference and consumer electronics; part 15 devices; over-modulation; RF feedback; off frequency signals","questions":[{"answer":"T7B01 (D)","question":"What can you do if you are told your FM handheld or mobile transceiver is over-deviating?","A":"A. Talk louder into the microphone","B":"B. Let the transceiver cool off","C":"C. Change to a higher power level","D":"D. Talk farther away from the microphone"},{"answer":"T7B02 (A)","question":"What would cause a broadcast AM or FM radio to receive an amateur radio transmission unintentionally?","A":"A. The receiver is unable to reject strong signals outside the AM or FM band","B":"B. The microphone gain of the transmitter is turned up too high","C":"C. The audio amplifier of the transmitter is overloaded","D":"D. The deviation of an FM transmitter is set too low"},{"answer":"T7B03 (D)","question":"Which of the following can cause radio frequency interference?","A":"A. Fundamental overload","B":"B. Harmonics","C":"C. Spurious emissions","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T7B04 (D)","question":"Which of the following is a way to reduce or eliminate interference from an amateur transmitter to a nearby telephone?","A":"A. Put a filter on the amateur transmitter","B":"B. Reduce the microphone gain","C":"C. Reduce the SWR on the transmitter transmission line","D":"D. Put an RF filter on the telephone"},{"answer":"T7B05 (A)","question":"How can overload of a non-amateur radio or TV receiver by an amateur signal be reduced or eliminated?","A":"A. Block the amateur signal with a filter at the antenna input of the affected receiver","B":"B. Block the interfering signal with a filter on the amateur transmitter","C":"C. Switch the transmitter from FM to SSB","D":"D. Switch the transmitter to a narrow-band mode"},{"answer":"T7B06 (A)","question":"Which of the following actions should you take if a neighbor tells you that your station’s transmissions are interfering with their radio or TV reception?","A":"A. Make sure that your station is functioning properly and that it does not cause interference to your own radio or television when it is tuned to the same channel","B":"B. Immediately turn off your transmitter and contact the nearest FCC office for assistance","C":"C. Tell them that your license gives you the right to transmit and nothing can be done to reduce the interference","D":"D. Install a harmonic doubler on the output of your transmitter and tune it until the interference is eliminated"},{"answer":"T7B07 (D)","question":"Which of the following can reduce overload to a VHF transceiver from a nearby FM broadcast station?","A":"A. RF preamplifier","B":"B. Double-shielded coaxial cable","C":"C. Using headphones instead of the speaker","D":"D. Band-reject filter"},{"answer":"T7B08 (D)","question":"What should you do if something in a neighbor’s home is causing harmful interference to your amateur station?","A":"A. Work with your neighbor to identify the offending device","B":"B. Politely inform your neighbor about the rules that prohibit the use of devices that cause interference","C":"C. Check your station and make sure it meets the standards of good amateur practice","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T7B09 (A)","question":"What is a Part 15 device?","A":"A. An unlicensed device that may emit low-powered radio signals on frequencies used by a licensed service","B":"B. An amplifier that has been type-certified for amateur radio","C":"C. A device for long-distance communications using special codes sanctioned by the International Amateur Radio Union","D":"D. A type of test set used to determine whether a transmitter complies with FCC regulation 91.15"},{"answer":"T7B10 (D)","question":"What might be a problem if you receive a report that your audio signal through the repeater is distorted or unintelligible?","A":"A. Your transmitter is slightly off frequency","B":"B. Your batteries are running low","C":"C. You are in a bad location","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T7B11 (C)","question":"What is a symptom of RF feedback in a transmitter or transceiver?","A":"A. Excessive SWR at the antenna connection","B":"B. The transmitter will not stay on the desired frequency","C":"C. Reports of garbled, distorted, or unintelligible voice transmissions","D":"D. Frequent blowing of power supply fuses"},{"answer":"T7B12 (D)","question":"What should be the first step to resolve cable TV interference from your ham radio transmission?","A":"A. Add a low-pass filter to the TV antenna input","B":"B. Add a high-pass filter to the TV antenna input","C":"C. Add a preamplifier to the TV antenna input","D":"D. Be sure all TV coaxial connectors are installed properly"}]},"T7C":{"section_name":"T7C - Antenna measurements and troubleshooting: measuring SWR; dummy loads; coaxial cables; causes of feed line failures","questions":[{"answer":"T7C01 (A)","question":"What is the primary purpose of a dummy load?","A":"A. To prevent transmitting signals over the air when making tests","B":"B. To prevent over-modulation of a transmitter","C":"C. To improve the efficiency of an antenna","D":"D. To improve the signal-to-noise ratio of a receiver"},{"answer":"T7C02 (B)","question":"Which of the following instruments can be used to determine if an antenna is resonant at the desired operating frequency?","A":"A. A VTVM","B":"B. An antenna analyzer","C":"C. A Q meter","D":"D. A frequency counter"},{"answer":"T7C03 (A)","question":"What, in general terms, is standing wave ratio (SWR)?","A":"A. A measure of how well a load is matched to a transmission line","B":"B. The ratio of high to low impedance in a feed line","C":"C. The transmitter efficiency ratio","D":"D. An indication of the quality of your station’s ground connection"},{"answer":"T7C04 (C)","question":"What reading on an SWR meter indicates a perfect impedance match between the antenna and the feed line?","A":"A. 2 to 1","B":"B. 1 to 3","C":"C. 1 to 1","D":"D. 10 to 1"},{"answer":"T7C05 (A)","question":"Why do most solid-state amateur radio transmitters reduce output power as SWR increases?","A":"A. To protect the output amplifier transistors","B":"B. To comply with FCC rules on spectral purity","C":"C. Because power supplies cannot supply enough current at high SWR","D":"D. To improve the impedance match to the feed line"},{"answer":"T7C06 (D)","question":"What does an SWR reading of 4:1 indicate?","A":"A. Loss of -4 dB","B":"B. Good impedance match","C":"C. Gain of +4 dB","D":"D. Impedance mismatch"},{"answer":"T7C07 (C)","question":"What happens to power lost in a feed line?","A":"A. It increases the SWR","B":"B. It comes back into your transmitter and could cause damage","C":"C. It is converted into heat","D":"D. It can cause distortion of your signal"},{"answer":"T7C08 (D)","question":"What instrument other than an SWR meter could you use to determine if a feed line and antenna are properly matched?","A":"A. Voltmeter","B":"B. Ohmmeter","C":"C. Iambic pentameter","D":"D. Directional wattmeter"},{"answer":"T7C09 (A)","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause for failure of coaxial cables?","A":"A. Moisture contamination","B":"B. Gamma rays","C":"C. The velocity factor exceeds 1.0","D":"D. Overloading"},{"answer":"T7C10 (D)","question":"Why should the outer jacket of coaxial cable be resistant to ultraviolet light?","A":"A. Ultraviolet resistant jackets prevent harmonic radiation","B":"B. Ultraviolet light can increase losses in the cable’s jacket","C":"C. Ultraviolet and RF signals can mix, causing interference","D":"D. Ultraviolet light can damage the jacket and allow water to enter the cable"},{"answer":"T7C11 (C)","question":"What is a disadvantage of air core coaxial cable when compared to foam or solid dielectric types?","A":"A. It has more loss per foot","B":"B. It cannot be used for VHF or UHF antennas","C":"C. It requires special techniques to prevent water absorption","D":"D. It cannot be used at below freezing temperatures"},{"answer":"T7C12 (B)","question":"What does a dummy load consist of?","A":"A. A high-gain amplifier and a TR switch","B":"B. A non-inductive resistor and a heat sink","C":"C. A low-voltage power supply and a DC relay","D":"D. A 50 ohm reactance used to terminate a transmission line"}]},"T7D":{"section_name":"T7D - Basic repair and testing: soldering; using basic test instruments; connecting a voltmeter, ammeter, or ohmmeter","questions":[{"answer":"T7D01 (B)","question":"Which instrument would you use to measure electric potential or electromotive force?","A":"A. An ammeter","B":"B. A voltmeter","C":"C. A wavemeter","D":"D. An ohmmeter"},{"answer":"T7D02 (B)","question":"What is the correct way to connect a voltmeter to a circuit?","A":"A. In series with the circuit","B":"B. In parallel with the circuit","C":"C. In quadrature with the circuit","D":"D. In phase with the circuit"},{"answer":"T7D03 (A)","question":"How is a simple ammeter connected to a circuit?","A":"A. In series with the circuit","B":"B. In parallel with the circuit","C":"C. In quadrature with the circuit","D":"D. In phase with the circuit"},{"answer":"T7D04 (D)","question":"Which instrument is used to measure electric current?","A":"A. An ohmmeter","B":"B. A wavemeter","C":"C. A voltmeter","D":"D. An ammeter"},{"answer":"T7D05 (D)","question":"What instrument is used to measure resistance?","A":"A. An oscilloscope","B":"B. A spectrum analyzer","C":"C. A noise bridge","D":"D. An ohmmeter"},{"answer":"T7D06 (C)","question":"Which of the following might damage a multimeter?","A":"A. Measuring a voltage too small for the chosen scale","B":"B. Leaving the meter in the milliamps position overnight","C":"C. Attempting to measure voltage when using the resistance setting","D":"D. Not allowing it to warm up properly"},{"answer":"T7D07 (D)","question":"Which of the following measurements are commonly made using a multimeter?","A":"A. SWR and RF power","B":"B. Signal strength and noise","C":"C. Impedance and reactance","D":"D. Voltage and resistance"},{"answer":"T7D08 (C)","question":"Which of the following types of solder is best for radio and electronic use?","A":"A. Acid-core solder","B":"B. Silver solder","C":"C. Rosin-core solder","D":"D. Aluminum solder"},{"answer":"T7D09 (C)","question":"What is the characteristic appearance of a cold solder joint?","A":"A. Dark black spots","B":"B. A bright or shiny surface","C":"C. A grainy or dull surface","D":"D. A greenish tint"},{"answer":"T7D10 (B)","question":"What is probably happening when an ohmmeter, connected across an unpowered circuit, initially indicates a low resistance and then shows increasing resistance with time?","A":"A. The ohmmeter is defective","B":"B. The circuit contains a large capacitor","C":"C. The circuit contains a large inductor","D":"D. The circuit is a relaxation oscillator"},{"answer":"T7D11 (B)","question":"Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring circuit resistance with an ohmmeter?","A":"A. Ensure that the applied voltages are correct","B":"B. Ensure that the circuit is not powered","C":"C. Ensure that the circuit is grounded","D":"D. Ensure that the circuit is operating at the correct frequency"},{"answer":"T7D12 (B)","question":"Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring high voltages with a voltmeter?","A":"A. Ensure that the voltmeter has very low impedance","B":"B. Ensure that the voltmeter and leads are rated for use at the voltages to be measured","C":"C. Ensure that the circuit is grounded through the voltmeter","D":"D. Ensure that the voltmeter is set to the correct frequency"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T8":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T8 - Modulation modes: amateur satellite operation; operating activities; non-voice and digital communications - [4 Exam Questions - 4 Groups]","section_groups":["T8A","T8B","T8C","T8D"],"T8A":{"name":"T8A - Modulation modes: bandwidth of various signals; choice of emission type","questions":[{"answer":"T8A01 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a form of amplitude modulation?","A":"A. Spread spectrum","B":"B. Packet radio","C":"C. Single sideband","D":"D. Phase shift keying (PSK)"},{"answer":"T8A02 (A)","question":"What type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF packet radio transmissions?","A":"A. FM","B":"B. SSB","C":"C. AM","D":"D. PSK"},{"answer":"T8A03 (C)","question":"Which type of voice mode is most often used for long-distance (weak signal) contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?","A":"A. FM","B":"B. DRM","C":"C. SSB","D":"D. PM"},{"answer":"T8A04 (D)","question":"Which type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF and UHF voice repeaters?","A":"A. AM","B":"B. SSB","C":"C. PSK","D":"D. FM"},{"answer":"T8A05 (C)","question":"Which of the following types of emission has the narrowest bandwidth?","A":"A. FM voice","B":"B. SSB voice","C":"C. CW","D":"D. Slow-scan TV"},{"answer":"T8A06 (A)","question":"Which sideband is normally used for 10 meter HF, VHF, and UHF single-sideband communications?","A":"A. Upper sideband","B":"B. Lower sideband","C":"C. Suppressed sideband","D":"D. Inverted sideband"},{"answer":"T8A07 (C)","question":"What is an advantage of single sideband (SSB) over FM for voice transmissions?","A":"A. SSB signals are easier to tune","B":"B. SSB signals are less susceptible to interference","C":"C. SSB signals have narrower bandwidth","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8A08 (B)","question":"What is the approximate bandwidth of a single sideband (SSB) voice signal?","A":"A. 1 kHz","B":"B. 3 kHz","C":"C. 6 kHz","D":"D. 15 kHz"},{"answer":"T8A09 (C)","question":"What is the approximate bandwidth of a VHF repeater FM phone signal?","A":"A. Less than 500 Hz","B":"B. About 150 kHz","C":"C. Between 10 and 15 kHz","D":"D. Between 50 and 125 kHz"},{"answer":"T8A10 (B)","question":"What is the typical bandwidth of analog fast-scan TV transmissions on the 70 centimeter band?","A":"A. More than 10 MHz","B":"B. About 6 MHz","C":"C. About 3 MHz","D":"D. About 1 MHz"},{"answer":"T8A11 (B)","question":"What is the approximate maximum bandwidth required to transmit a CW signal?","A":"A. 2.4 kHz","B":"B. 150 Hz","C":"C. 1000 Hz","D":"D. 15 kHz"}]},"T8B":{"section_name":"T8B - Amateur satellite operation; Doppler shift; basic orbits; operating protocols; transmitter power considerations; telemetry and telecommand; satellite tracking","questions":[{"answer":"T8B01 (C)","question":"What telemetry information is typically transmitted by satellite beacons?","A":"A. The signal strength of received signals","B":"B. Time of day accurate to plus or minus 1/10 second","C":"C. Health and status of the satellite","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8B02 (B)","question":"What is the impact of using too much effective radiated power on a satellite uplink?","A":"A. Possibility of commanding the satellite to an improper mode","B":"B. Blocking access by other users","C":"C. Overloading the satellite batteries","D":"D. Possibility of rebooting the satellite control computer"},{"answer":"T8B03 (D)","question":"Which of the following are provided by satellite tracking programs?","A":"A. Maps showing the real-time position of the satellite track over the earth","B":"B. The time, azimuth, and elevation of the start, maximum altitude, and end of a pass","C":"C. The apparent frequency of the satellite transmission, including effects of Doppler shift","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8B04 (D)","question":"What mode of transmission is commonly used by amateur radio satellites?","A":"A. SSB","B":"B. FM","C":"C. CW/data","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8B05 (D)","question":"What is a satellite beacon?","A":"A. The primary transmit antenna on the satellite","B":"B. An indicator light that shows where to point your antenna","C":"C. A reflective surface on the satellite","D":"D. A transmission from a satellite that contains status information"},{"answer":"T8B06 (B)","question":"Which of the following are inputs to a satellite tracking program?","A":"A. The weight of the satellite","B":"B. The Keplerian elements","C":"C. The last observed time of zero Doppler shift","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8B07 (C)","question":"With regard to satellite communications, what is Doppler shift?","A":"A. A change in the satellite orbit","B":"B. A mode where the satellite receives signals on one band and transmits on another","C":"C. An observed change in signal frequency caused by relative motion between the satellite and the earth station","D":"D. A special digital communications mode for some satellites"},{"answer":"T8B08 (B)","question":"What is meant by the statement that a satellite is operating in mode U/V?","A":"A. The satellite uplink is in the 15 meter band and the downlink is in the 10 meter band","B":"B. The satellite uplink is in the 70 centimeter band and the downlink is in the 2 meter band","C":"C. The satellite operates using ultraviolet frequencies","D":"D. The satellite frequencies are usually variable"},{"answer":"T8B09 (B)","question":"What causes spin fading of satellite signals?","A":"A. Circular polarized noise interference radiated from the sun","B":"B. Rotation of the satellite and its antennas","C":"C. Doppler shift of the received signal","D":"D. Interfering signals within the satellite uplink band"},{"answer":"T8B10 (C)","question":"What do the initials LEO tell you about an amateur satellite?","A":"A. The satellite battery is in Low Energy Operation mode","B":"B. The satellite is performing a Lunar Ejection Orbit maneuver","C":"C. The satellite is in a Low Earth Orbit","D":"D. The satellite uses Light Emitting Optics"},{"answer":"T8B11 (A)","question":"Who may receive telemetry from a space station?","A":"A. Anyone who can receive the telemetry signal","B":"B. A licensed radio amateur with a transmitter equipped for interrogating the satellite","C":"C. A licensed radio amateur who has been certified by the protocol developer","D":"D. A licensed radio amateur who has registered for an access code from AMSAT"},{"answer":"T8B12 (C)","question":"Which of the following is a good way to judge whether your uplink power is neither too low nor too high?","A":"A. Check your signal strength report in the telemetry data","B":"B. Listen for distortion on your downlink signal","C":"C. Your signal strength on the downlink should be about the same as the beacon","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"}]},"T8C":{"section_name":"T8C - Operating activities: radio direction finding; radio control; contests; linking over the internet; grid locators","questions":[{"answer":"T8C01 (C)","question":"Which of the following methods is used to locate sources of noise interference or jamming?","A":"A. Echolocation","B":"B. Doppler radar","C":"C. Radio direction finding","D":"D. Phase locking"},{"answer":"T8C02 (B)","question":"Which of these items would be useful for a hidden transmitter hunt?","A":"A. Calibrated SWR meter","B":"B. A directional antenna","C":"C. A calibrated noise bridge","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8C03 (A)","question":"What operating activity involves contacting as many stations as possible during a specified period?","A":"A. Contesting","B":"B. Net operations","C":"C. Public service events","D":"D. Simulated emergency exercises"},{"answer":"T8C04 (C)","question":"Which of the following is good procedure when contacting another station in a radio contest?","A":"A. Sign only the last two letters of your call if there are many other stations calling","B":"B. Contact the station twice to be sure that you are in his log","C":"C. Send only the minimum information needed for proper identification and the contest exchange","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8C05 (A)","question":"What is a grid locator?","A":"A. A letter-number designator assigned to a geographic location","B":"B. A letter-number designator assigned to an azimuth and elevation","C":"C. An instrument for neutralizing a final amplifier","D":"D. An instrument for radio direction finding"},{"answer":"T8C06 (B)","question":"How is access to some IRLP nodes accomplished?","A":"A. By obtaining a password that is sent via voice to the node","B":"B. By using DTMF signals","C":"C. By entering the proper internet password","D":"D. By using CTCSS tone codes"},{"answer":"T8C07 (D)","question":"What is meant by Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP) as used in amateur radio?","A":"A. A set of rules specifying how to identify your station when linked over the internet to another station","B":"B. A set of guidelines for contacting DX stations during contests using internet access","C":"C. A technique for measuring the modulation quality of a transmitter using remote sites monitored via the internet","D":"D. A method of delivering voice communications over the internet using digital techniques"},{"answer":"T8C08 (A)","question":"What is the Internet Radio Linking Project (IRLP)?","A":"A. A technique to connect amateur radio systems, such as repeaters, via the internet using Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP)","B":"B. A system for providing access to websites via amateur radio","C":"C. A system for informing amateurs in real time of the frequency of active DX stations","D":"D. A technique for measuring signal strength of an amateur transmitter via the internet"},{"answer":"T8C09 (D)","question":"How might you obtain a list of active nodes that use VoIP?","A":"A. By subscribing to an on line service","B":"B. From on line repeater lists maintained by the local repeater frequency coordinator","C":"C. From a repeater directory","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8C10 (D)","question":"What must be done before you may use the EchoLink system to communicate using a repeater?","A":"A. You must complete the required EchoLink training","B":"B. You must have purchased a license to use the EchoLink software","C":"C. You must be sponsored by a current EchoLink user","D":"D. You must register your call sign and provide proof of license"},{"answer":"T8C11 (A)","question":"What name is given to an amateur radio station that is used to connect other amateur stations to the internet?","A":"A. A gateway","B":"B. A repeater","C":"C. A digipeater","D":"D. A beacon"}]},"T8D":{"section_name":"T8D - Non-voice and digital communications: image signals; digital modes; CW; packet radio; PSK31; APRS; error detection and correction; NTSC; amateur radio networking; Digital Mobile/Migration Radio","questions":[{"answer":"T8D01 (D)","question":"Which of the following is a digital communications mode?","A":"A. Packet radio","B":"B. IEEE 802.11","C":"C. JT65","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8D02 (A)","question":"What does the term “APRS” mean?","A":"A. Automatic Packet Reporting System","B":"B. Associated Public Radio Station","C":"C. Auto Planning Radio Set-up","D":"D. Advanced Polar Radio System"},{"answer":"T8D03 (D)","question":"Which of the following devices is used to provide data to the transmitter when sending automatic position reports from a mobile amateur radio station?","A":"A. The vehicle speedometer","B":"B. A WWV receiver","C":"C. A connection to a broadcast FM sub-carrier receiver","D":"D. A Global Positioning System receiver"},{"answer":"T8D04 (C)","question":"What type of transmission is indicated by the term \\"NTSC?\\"","A":"A. A Normal Transmission mode in Static Circuit","B":"B. A special mode for earth satellite uplink","C":"C. An analog fast scan color TV signal","D":"D. A frame compression scheme for TV signals"},{"answer":"T8D05 (A)","question":"Which of the following is an application of APRS (Automatic Packet Reporting System)?","A":"A. Providing real-time tactical digital communications in conjunction with a map showing the locations of stations","B":"B. Showing automatically the number of packets transmitted via PACTOR during a specific time interval","C":"C. Providing voice over internet connection between repeaters","D":"D. Providing information on the number of stations signed into a repeater"},{"answer":"T8D06 (B)","question":"What does the abbreviation \\"PSK\\" mean?","A":"A. Pulse Shift Keying","B":"B. Phase Shift Keying","C":"C. Packet Short Keying","D":"D. Phased Slide Keying"},{"answer":"T8D07 (A)","question":"Which of the following best describes DMR (Digital Mobile Radio)?","A":"A. A technique for time-multiplexing two digital voice signals on a single 12.5 kHz repeater channel","B":"B. An automatic position tracking mode for FM mobiles communicating through repeaters","C":"C. An automatic computer logging technique for hands-off logging when communicating while operating a vehicle","D":"D. A digital technique for transmitting on two repeater inputs simultaneously for automatic error correction"},{"answer":"T8D08 (D)","question":"Which of the following may be included in packet transmissions?","A":"A. A check sum that permits error detection","B":"B. A header that contains the call sign of the station to which the information is being sent","C":"C. Automatic repeat request in case of error","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8D09 (C)","question":"What code is used when sending CW in the amateur bands?","A":"A. Baudot","B":"B. Hamming","C":"C. International Morse","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8D10 (D)","question":"Which of the following operating activities is supported by digital mode software in the WSJT suite?","A":"A. Moonbounce or Earth-Moon-Earth","B":"B. Weak-signal propagation beacons","C":"C. Meteor scatter","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T8D11 (C)","question":"What is an ARQ transmission system?","A":"A. A special transmission format limited to video signals","B":"B. A system used to encrypt command signals to an amateur radio satellite","C":"C. A digital scheme whereby the receiving station detects errors and sends a request to the sending station to retransmit the information","D":"D. A method of compressing the data in a message so more information can be sent in a shorter time"},{"answer":"T8D12 (A)","question":"Which of the following best describes Broadband-Hamnet(TM), also referred to as a high-speed multi-media network?","A":"A. An amateur-radio-based data network using commercial Wi-Fi gear with modified firmware","B":"B. A wide-bandwidth digital voice mode employing DRM protocols","C":"C. A satellite communications network using modified commercial satellite TV hardware","D":"D. An internet linking protocol used to network repeaters"},{"answer":"T8D13 (B)","question":"What is FT8?","A":"A. A wideband FM voice mode","B":"B. A digital mode capable of operating in low signal-to-noise conditions that transmits on 15-second intervals","C":"C. An eight channel multiplex mode for FM repeaters","D":"D. A digital slow scan TV mode with forward error correction and automatic color compensation"},{"answer":"T8D14 (C)","question":"What is an electronic keyer?","A":"A. A device for switching antennas from transmit to receive","B":"B. A device for voice activated switching from receive to transmit","C":"C. A device that assists in manual sending of Morse code","D":"D. An interlock to prevent unauthorized use of a radio"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T9":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T9 - Antennas and feed lines - [2 Exam Questions - 2 Groups]","section_groups":["T9A","T9B"],"T9A":{"name":"T9A - Antennas: vertical and horizontal polarization; concept of gain; common portable and mobile antennas; relationships between resonant length and frequency; concept of dipole antennas","questions":[{"answer":"T9A01 (C)","question":"What is a beam antenna?","A":"A. An antenna built from aluminum I-beams","B":"B. An omnidirectional antenna invented by Clarence Beam","C":"C. An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction","D":"D. An antenna that reverses the phase of received signals"},{"answer":"T9A02 (A)","question":"Which of the following describes a type of antenna loading?","A":"A. Inserting an inductor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it electrically longer","B":"B. Inserting a resistor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it resonant","C":"C. Installing a spring in the base of a mobile vertical antenna to make it more flexible","D":"D. Strengthening the radiating elements of a beam antenna to better resist wind damage"},{"answer":"T9A03 (B)","question":"Which of the following describes a simple dipole oriented parallel to the Earth\'s surface?","A":"A. A ground-wave antenna","B":"B. A horizontally polarized antenna","C":"C. A rhombic antenna","D":"D. A vertically polarized antenna"},{"answer":"T9A04 (A)","question":"What is a disadvantage of the “rubber duck” antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers when compared to a full-sized quarter-wave antenna?","A":"A. It does not transmit or receive as effectively","B":"B. It transmits only circularly polarized signals","C":"C. If the rubber end cap is lost, it will unravel very easily","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T9A05 (C)","question":"How would you change a dipole antenna to make it resonant on a higher frequency?","A":"A. Lengthen it","B":"B. Insert coils in series with radiating wires","C":"C. Shorten it","D":"D. Add capacitive loading to the ends of the radiating wires"},{"answer":"T9A06 (C)","question":"What type of antennas are the quad, Yagi, and dish?","A":"A. Non-resonant antennas","B":"B. Log periodic antennas","C":"C. Directional antennas","D":"D. Isotropic antennas"},{"answer":"T9A07 (A)","question":"What is a disadvantage of using a handheld VHF transceiver, with its integral antenna, inside a vehicle?","A":"A. Signals might not propagate well due to the shielding effect of the vehicle","B":"B. It might cause the transceiver to overheat","C":"C. The SWR might decrease, decreasing the signal strength","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T9A08 (C)","question":"What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?","A":"A. 112","B":"B. 50","C":"C. 19","D":"D. 12"},{"answer":"T9A09 (C)","question":"What is the approximate length, in inches, of a half-wavelength 6 meter dipole antenna?","A":"A. 6","B":"B. 50","C":"C. 112","D":"D. 236"},{"answer":"T9A10 (C)","question":"In which direction does a half-wave dipole antenna radiate the strongest signal?","A":"A. Equally in all directions","B":"B. Off the ends of the antenna","C":"C. Broadside to the antenna","D":"D. In the direction of the feed line"},{"answer":"T9A11 (C)","question":"What is the gain of an antenna?","A":"A. The additional power that is added to the transmitter power","B":"B. The additional power that is lost in the antenna when transmitting on a higher frequency","C":"C. The increase in signal strength in a specified direction compared to a reference antenna","D":"D. The increase in impedance on receive or transmit compared to a reference antenna"},{"answer":"T9A12 (A)","question":"What is an advantage of using a properly mounted 5/8 wavelength antenna for VHF or UHF mobile service?","A":"A. It has a lower radiation angle and more gain than a 1/4 wavelength antenna","B":"B. It has very high angle radiation for better communicating through a repeater","C":"C. It eliminates distortion caused by reflected signals","D":"D. It has 10 times the power gain of a 1/4 wavelength design"}]},"T9B":{"section_name":"T9B - Feed lines: types, attenuation vs frequency, selecting; SWR concepts; Antenna tuners (couplers); RF Connectors: selecting, weather protection","questions":[{"answer":"T9B01 (B)","question":"Why is it important to have low SWR when using coaxial cable feed line?","A":"A. To reduce television interference","B":"B. To reduce signal loss","C":"C. To prolong antenna life","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T9B02 (B)","question":"What is the impedance of most coaxial cables used in amateur radio installations?","A":"A. 8 ohms","B":"B. 50 ohms","C":"C. 600 ohms","D":"D. 12 ohms"},{"answer":"T9B03 (A)","question":"Why is coaxial cable the most common feed line selected for amateur radio antenna systems?","A":"A. It is easy to use and requires few special installation considerations","B":"B. It has less loss than any other type of feed line","C":"C. It can handle more power than any other type of feed line","D":"D. It is less expensive than any other type of feed line"},{"answer":"T9B04 (A)","question":"What is the major function of an antenna tuner (antenna coupler)?","A":"A. It matches the antenna system impedance to the transceiver\'s output impedance","B":"B. It helps a receiver automatically tune in weak stations","C":"C. It allows an antenna to be used on both transmit and receive","D":"D. It automatically selects the proper antenna for the frequency band being used"},{"answer":"T9B05 (D)","question":"In general, what happens as the frequency of a signal passing through coaxial cable is increased?","A":"A. The characteristic impedance decreases","B":"B. The loss decreases","C":"C. The characteristic impedance increases","D":"D. The loss increases"},{"answer":"T9B06 (B)","question":"Which of the following connectors is most suitable for frequencies above 400 MHz?","A":"A. A UHF (PL-259/SO-239) connector","B":"B. A Type N connector","C":"C. An RS-213 connector","D":"D. A DB-25 connector"},{"answer":"T9B07 (C)","question":"Which of the following is true of PL-259 type coax connectors?","A":"A. They are preferred for microwave operation","B":"B. They are watertight","C":"C. They are commonly used at HF frequencies","D":"D. They are a bayonet type connector"},{"answer":"T9B08 (A)","question":"Why should coax connectors exposed to the weather be sealed against water intrusion?","A":"A. To prevent an increase in feed line loss","B":"B. To prevent interference to telephones","C":"C. To keep the jacket from becoming loose","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T9B09 (B)","question":"What can cause erratic changes in SWR readings?","A":"A. The transmitter is being modulated","B":"B. A loose connection in an antenna or a feed line","C":"C. The transmitter is being over-modulated","D":"D. Interference from other stations is distorting your signal"},{"answer":"T9B10 (C)","question":"What is the electrical difference between RG-58 and RG-8 coaxial cable?","A":"A. There is no significant difference between the two types","B":"B. RG-58 cable has two shields","C":"C. RG-8 cable has less loss at a given frequency","D":"D. RG-58 cable can handle higher power levels"},{"answer":"T9B11 (C)","question":"Which of the following types of feed line has the lowest loss at VHF and UHF?","A":"A. 50-ohm flexible coax","B":"B. Multi-conductor unbalanced cable","C":"C. Air-insulated hard line","D":"D. 75-ohm flexible coax"}]}},"SUBELEMENT_T0":{"section_name":"SUBELEMENT T0 - Electrical safety: AC and DC power circuits; antenna installation; RF hazards - [3 Exam Questions - 3 Groups]","section_groups":["T0A","T0B","T0C"],"T0A":{"name":"T0A - Power circuits and hazards: hazardous voltages; fuses and circuit breakers; grounding; lightning protection; battery safety; electrical code compliance","questions":[{"answer":"T0A01 (B)","question":"Which of the following is a safety hazard of a 12-volt storage battery?","A":"A. Touching both terminals with the hands can cause electrical shock","B":"B. Shorting the terminals can cause burns, fire, or an explosion","C":"C. RF emissions from the battery","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A02 (D)","question":"What health hazard is presented by electrical current flowing through the body?","A":"A. It may cause injury by heating tissue","B":"B. It may disrupt the electrical functions of cells","C":"C. It may cause involuntary muscle contractions","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A03 (C)","question":"In the United States, what is connected to the green wire in a three-wire electrical AC plug?","A":"A. Neutral","B":"B. Hot","C":"C. Equipment ground","D":"D. The white wire"},{"answer":"T0A04 (B)","question":"What is the purpose of a fuse in an electrical circuit?","A":"A. To prevent power supply ripple from damaging a circuit","B":"B. To interrupt power in case of overload","C":"C. To limit current to prevent shocks","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A05 (C)","question":"Why is it unwise to install a 20-ampere fuse in the place of a 5-ampere fuse?","A":"A. The larger fuse would be likely to blow because it is rated for higher current","B":"B. The power supply ripple would greatly increase","C":"C. Excessive current could cause a fire","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A06 (D)","question":"What is a good way to guard against electrical shock at your station?","A":"A. Use three-wire cords and plugs for all AC powered equipment","B":"B. Connect all AC powered station equipment to a common safety ground","C":"C. Use a circuit protected by a ground-fault interrupter","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A07 (D)","question":"Which of these precautions should be taken when installing devices for lightning protection in a coaxial cable feed line?","A":"A. Include a parallel bypass switch for each protector so that it can be switched out of the circuit when running high power","B":"B. Include a series switch in the ground line of each protector to prevent RF overload from inadvertently damaging the protector","C":"C. Keep the ground wires from each protector separate and connected to station ground","D":"D. Mount all of the protectors on a metal plate that is in turn connected to an external ground rod"},{"answer":"T0A08 (A)","question":"What safety equipment should always be included in home-built equipment that is powered from 120V AC power circuits?","A":"A. A fuse or circuit breaker in series with the AC hot conductor","B":"B. An AC voltmeter across the incoming power source","C":"C. An inductor in parallel with the AC power source","D":"D. A capacitor in series with the AC power source"},{"answer":"T0A09 (C)","question":"What should be done to all external ground rods or earth connections?","A":"A. Waterproof them with silicone caulk or electrical tape","B":"B. Keep them as far apart as possible","C":"C. Bond them together with heavy wire or conductive strap","D":"D. Tune them for resonance on the lowest frequency of operation"},{"answer":"T0A10 (A)","question":"What can happen if a lead-acid storage battery is charged or discharged too quickly?","A":"A. The battery could overheat, give off flammable gas, or explode","B":"B. The voltage can become reversed","C":"C. The memory effect will reduce the capacity of the battery","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0A11 (D)","question":"What kind of hazard might exist in a power supply when it is turned off and disconnected?","A":"A. Static electricity could damage the grounding system","B":"B. Circulating currents inside the transformer might cause damage","C":"C. The fuse might blow if you remove the cover","D":"D. You might receive an electric shock from the charge stored in large capacitors"}]},"T0B":{"section_name":"T0B - Antenna safety: tower safety and grounding; erecting an antenna support; safely installing an antenna","questions":[{"answer":"T0B01 (C)","question":"When should members of a tower work team wear a hard hat and safety glasses?","A":"A. At all times except when climbing the tower","B":"B. At all times except when belted firmly to the tower","C":"C. At all times when any work is being done on the tower","D":"D. Only when the tower exceeds 30 feet in height"},{"answer":"T0B02 (C)","question":"What is a good precaution to observe before climbing an antenna tower?","A":"A. Make sure that you wear a grounded wrist strap","B":"B. Remove all tower grounding connections","C":"C. Put on a carefully inspected climbing harness(fall arrester)and safety glasses","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0B03 (D)","question":"Under what circumstances is it safe to climb a tower without a helper or observer?","A":"A. When no electrical work is being performed","B":"B. When no mechanical work is being performed","C":"C. When the work being done is not more than 20 feet above the ground","D":"D. Never"},{"answer":"T0B04 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an important safety precaution to observe when putting up an antenna tower?","A":"A. Wear a ground strap connected to your wrist at all times","B":"B. Insulate the base of the tower to avoid lightning strikes","C":"C. Look for and stay clear of any overhead electrical wires","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0B05 (C)","question":"What is the purpose of a gin pole?","A":"A. To temporarily replace guy wires","B":"B. To be used in place of a safety harness","C":"C. To lift tower sections or antennas","D":"D. To provide a temporary ground"},{"answer":"T0B06 (D)","question":"What is the minimum safe distance from a power line to allow when installing an antenna?","A":"A. Half the width of your property","B":"B. The height of the power line above ground","C":"C. 1/2 wavelength at the operating frequency","D":"D. Enough so that if the antenna falls unexpectedly, no part of it can come closer than 10 feet to the power wires"},{"answer":"T0B07 (C)","question":"Which of the following is an important safety rule to remember when using a crank-up tower?","A":"A. This type of tower must never be painted","B":"B. This type of tower must never be grounded","C":"C. This type of tower must not be climbed unless retracted or mechanical safety locking devices have been installed","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0B08 (C)","question":"What is considered to be a proper grounding method for a tower?","A":"A. A single four-foot ground rod, driven into the ground no more than 12 inches from the base","B":"B. A ferrite-core RF choke connected between the tower and ground","C":"C. Separate eight-foot long ground rods for each tower leg, bonded to the tower and each other","D":"D. A connection between the tower base and a cold water pipe"},{"answer":"T0B09 (C)","question":"Why should you avoid attaching an antenna to a utility pole?","A":"A. The antenna will not work properly because of induced voltages","B":"B. The utility company will charge you an extra monthly fee","C":"C. The antenna could contact high-voltage power lines","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0B10 (C)","question":"Which of the following is true when installing grounding conductors used for lightning protection?","A":"A. Only non-insulated wire must be used","B":"B. Wires must be carefully routed with precise right-angle bends","C":"C. Sharp bends must be avoided","D":"D. Common grounds must be avoided"},{"answer":"T0B11 (B)","question":"Which of the following establishes grounding requirements for an amateur radio tower or antenna?","A":"A. FCC Part 97 Rules","B":"B. Local electrical codes","C":"C. FAA tower lighting regulations","D":"D. UL recommended practices"},{"answer":"T0B12 (C)","question":"Which of the following is good practice when installing ground wires on a tower for lightning protection?","A":"A. Put a loop in the ground connection to prevent water damage to the ground system","B":"B. Make sure that all bends in the ground wires are clean, right-angle bends","C":"C. Ensure that connections are short and direct","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0B13 (B)","question":"What is the purpose of a safety wire through a turnbuckle used to tension guy lines?","A":"A. Secure the guy if the turnbuckle breaks","B":"B. Prevent loosening of the guy line from vibration","C":"C. Prevent theft or vandalism","D":"D. Deter unauthorized climbing of the tower"}]},"T0C":{"section_name":"T0C - RF hazards: radiation exposure; proximity to antennas; recognized safe power levels; exposure to others; radiation types; duty cycle","questions":[{"answer":"T0C01 (D)","question":"What type of radiation are VHF and UHF radio signals?","A":"A. Gamma radiation","B":"B. Ionizing radiation","C":"C. Alpha radiation","D":"D. Non-ionizing radiation"},{"answer":"T0C02 (B)","question":"Which of the following frequencies has the lowest value for Maximum Permissible Exposure limit?","A":"A. 3.5 MHz","B":"B. 50 MHz","C":"C. 440 MHz","D":"D. 1296 MHz"},{"answer":"T0C03 (C)","question":"What is the maximum power level that an amateur radio station may use at VHF frequencies before an RF exposure evaluation is required?","A":"A. 1500 watts PEP transmitter output","B":"B. 1 watt forward power","C":"C. 50 watts PEP at the antenna","D":"D. 50 watts PEP reflected power"},{"answer":"T0C04 (D)","question":"What factors affect the RF exposure of people near an amateur station antenna?","A":"A. Frequency and power level of the RF field","B":"B. Distance from the antenna to a person","C":"C. Radiation pattern of the antenna","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0C05 (D)","question":"Why do exposure limits vary with frequency?","A":"A. Lower frequency RF fields have more energy than higher frequency fields","B":"B. Lower frequency RF fields do not penetrate the human body","C":"C. Higher frequency RF fields are transient in nature","D":"D. The human body absorbs more RF energy at some frequencies than at others"},{"answer":"T0C06 (D)","question":"Which of the following is an acceptable method to determine that your station complies with FCC RF exposure regulations?","A":"A. By calculation based on FCC OET Bulletin 65","B":"B. By calculation based on computer modeling","C":"C. By measurement of field strength using calibrated equipment","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0C07 (B)","question":"What could happen if a person accidentally touched your antenna while you were transmitting?","A":"A. Touching the antenna could cause television interference","B":"B. They might receive a painful RF burn","C":"C. They might develop radiation poisoning","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0C08 (A)","question":"Which of the following actions might amateur operators take to prevent exposure to RF radiation in excess of FCC-supplied limits?","A":"A. Relocate antennas","B":"B. Relocate the transmitter","C":"C. Increase the duty cycle","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0C09 (B)","question":"How can you make sure your station stays in compliance with RF safety regulations?","A":"A. By informing the FCC of any changes made in your station","B":"B. By re-evaluating the station whenever an item of equipment is changed","C":"C. By making sure your antennas have low SWR","D":"D. All of these choices are correct"},{"answer":"T0C10 (A)","question":"Why is duty cycle one of the factors used to determine safe RF radiation exposure levels?","A":"A. It affects the average exposure of people to radiation","B":"B. It affects the peak exposure of people to radiation","C":"C. It takes into account the antenna feed line loss","D":"D. It takes into account the thermal effects of the final amplifier"},{"answer":"T0C11 (C)","question":"What is the definition of duty cycle during the averaging time for RF exposure?","A":"A. The difference between the lowest power output and the highest power output of a transmitter","B":"B. The difference between the PEP and average power output of a transmitter","C":"C. The percentage of time that a transmitter is transmitting","D":"D. The percentage of time that a transmitter is not transmitting"},{"answer":"T0C12 (A)","question":"How does RF radiation differ from ionizing radiation (radioactivity)?","A":"A. RF radiation does not have sufficient energy to cause genetic damage","B":"B. RF radiation can only be detected with an RF dosimeter","C":"C. RF radiation is limited in range to a few feet","D":"D. RF radiation is perfectly safe"},{"answer":"T0C13 (C)","question":"If the averaging time for exposure is 6 minutes, how much power density is permitted if the signal is present for 3 minutes and absent for 3 minutes rather than being present for the entire 6 minutes?","A":"A. 3 times as much","B":"B. 1/2 as much","C":"C. 2 times as much","D":"D. There is no adjustment allowed for shorter exposure times"}]}}}');const A={class:"container-lg pagebreak"},w={class:"card"},C={class:"card-body"},B={class:"row text-start"},D={class:"row"},y={class:"input-group mb-3"},T=["name"],b={id:"label-a",class:"text-wrap text-start ms-2"},v={class:"row"},q={class:"input-group mb-3"},W=["name"],F={id:"label-b",class:"text-wrap text-start ms-2"},S={class:"row"},k={class:"input-group mb-3"},E=["name"],R={id:"label-c",class:"text-wrap text-start ms-2"},H={class:"row mb-3"},x={class:"input-group"},z=["name"],M={id:"label-d",class:"text-wrap text-start ms-2"};function I(e,t,n,i,s,c){return(0,o.wg)(),(0,o.iD)("div",A,[(0,o._)("div",w,[(0,o._)("div",C,[(0,o._)("h3",B,(0,r.zw)(n.question),1),(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("h5",{class:"row"},(0,r.zw)(n.answer),513),[[a.F8,e.display_answers]]),(0,o._)("div",D,[(0,o._)("div",y,[(0,o._)("div",{class:(0,r.C_)(["input-group-text",c.getAnswerClass("A")])},[(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("input",{type:"radio",name:n.question,value:"A",class:"form-check-input mt-0","aria-describedby":"label-a","onUpdate:modelValue":t[0]||(t[0]=t=>e.pick=t),onChange:t[1]||(t[1]=(...e)=>c.selectAnswer&&c.selectAnswer(...e))},null,40,T),[[a.G2,e.pick]]),(0,o._)("span",b,(0,r.zw)(n.a),1)],2)])]),(0,o._)("div",v,[(0,o._)("div",q,[(0,o._)("div",{class:(0,r.C_)(["input-group-text",c.getAnswerClass("B")])},[(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("input",{type:"radio",name:n.question,value:"B",class:"form-check-input mt-0","aria-describedby":"label-b","onUpdate:modelValue":t[2]||(t[2]=t=>e.pick=t),onChange:t[3]||(t[3]=(...e)=>c.selectAnswer&&c.selectAnswer(...e))},null,40,W),[[a.G2,e.pick]]),(0,o._)("span",F,(0,r.zw)(n.b),1)],2)])]),(0,o._)("div",S,[(0,o._)("div",k,[(0,o._)("div",{class:(0,r.C_)(["input-group-text",c.getAnswerClass("C")])},[(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("input",{type:"radio",name:n.question,value:"C",class:"form-check-input mt-0","aria-describedby":"label-c","onUpdate:modelValue":t[4]||(t[4]=t=>e.pick=t),onChange:t[5]||(t[5]=(...e)=>c.selectAnswer&&c.selectAnswer(...e))},null,40,E),[[a.G2,e.pick]]),(0,o._)("span",R,(0,r.zw)(n.c),1)],2)])]),(0,o._)("div",H,[(0,o._)("div",x,[(0,o._)("div",{class:(0,r.C_)(["input-group-text",c.getAnswerClass("D")])},[(0,o.wy)((0,o._)("input",{type:"radio",name:n.question,value:"D",class:"form-check-input mt-0","aria-describedby":"label-d","onUpdate:modelValue":t[6]||(t[6]=t=>e.pick=t),onChange:t[7]||(t[7]=(...e)=>c.selectAnswer&&c.selectAnswer(...e))},null,40,z),[[a.G2,e.pick]]),(0,o._)("span",M,(0,r.zw)(n.d),1)],2)])])])])])}var _=n(65);const P=/\(([^)]+)\)/,L=/\[(.*?)\]/;var U={name:"ExamQuestion",props:{question:String,answer:String,a:String,b:String,c:String,d:String},data:function(){return{pick:""}},computed:{correct_answer(){return P.exec(this.answer)[1]},fcc_hint(){const e=L.exec(this.answer);if(e&&e.length>0){const t=e[1].split(",");for(const[e,n]of t.entries())t[e]=n.replace(/[^0-9$.,]/g,"");return t}return""},...(0,_.rn)(["display_answers"])},methods:{selectAnswer(){this.$emit("selectAnswer",{answer:this.answer,pick:this.pick})},getAnswerClass(e){if(this.display_answers)return{active:!0,"alert-success":e==this.correct_answer,"alert-danger":e!=this.correct_answer}}}},O=n(89);const V=(0,O.Z)(U,[["render",I],["__scopeId","data-v-6a30d6fb"]]);var N=V;const G=/\(([^)]+)\)/;var j={name:"TechnicalExam",components:{ExamQuestion:N},data:function(){return{examPoolData:g,score_sheet:{},total_questions:0,correct_answers:0,passed:!1}},methods:{generateExam(){this.score_sheet={},this.total_questions=0,this.correct_answers=0;for(let e of this.activeExamPool["subelements"])for(let t of this.activeExamPool[e]["section_groups"]){const n=this.examPoolData[e][t]["questions"][Math.floor(Math.random()*this.examPoolData[e][t]["questions"].length)];this.activeExamPool[e][t]["questions"]=[n],this.score_sheet[n.answer]="",this.total_questions+=1}},onSelectAnswer(e){this.score_sheet[e.answer]=e.pick},gradeExam(){this.correct_answers=0;for(const e in this.score_sheet){const t=G.exec(e);t[1]===this.score_sheet[e]&&(this.correct_answers+=1)}this.$store.commit("setDisplayAnswers",!0),this.correct_answers>=26?this.passed=!0:this.passed=!1}},computed:{examTitle(){return this.examPoolData["exam_title"]},examDateRange(){return this.examPoolData["exam_effective_daterange"]},activeExamPool(){const e=JSON.parse(JSON.stringify(this.examPoolData));for(let t of e["subelements"])for(let n of e[t]["section_groups"])e[t][n]["questions"]=[];return e},...(0,_.rn)(["display_answers"])},created(){this.generateExam()}};const Q=(0,O.Z)(j,[["render",p]]);var Y=Q,K={name:"App",components:{TechnicalExam:Y}};const X=(0,O.Z)(K,[["render",i]]);var Z=X,J=n(7192);const $={isEnabled:!0,logLevel:"debug",stringifyArguments:!1,showLogLevel:!0,showMethodName:!0,separator:"|",showConsoleColors:!0},ee=(0,J.hu)($);ee.debug("logger setup");var te=(0,_.MT)({state:{display_answers:!1,score_sheet:[]},mutations:{setDisplayAnswers(e,t){e.display_answers=t}},actions:{},modules:{}});n(8937);(0,a.ri)(Z).use(te).mount("#app")}},t={};function n(a){var o=t[a];if(void 0!==o)return o.exports;var i=t[a]={exports:{}};return e[a](i,i.exports,n),i.exports}n.m=e,function(){var e=[];n.O=function(t,a,o,i){if(!a){var r=1/0;for(h=0;h<e.length;h++){a=e[h][0],o=e[h][1],i=e[h][2];for(var s=!0,c=0;c<a.length;c++)(!1&i||r>=i)&&Object.keys(n.O).every((function(e){return n.O[e](a[c])}))?a.splice(c--,1):(s=!1,i<r&&(r=i));if(s){e.splice(h--,1);var l=o();void 0!==l&&(t=l)}}return t}i=i||0;for(var h=e.length;h>0&&e[h-1][2]>i;h--)e[h]=e[h-1];e[h]=[a,o,i]}}(),function(){n.n=function(e){var t=e&&e.__esModule?function(){return e["default"]}:function(){return e};return n.d(t,{a:t}),t}}(),function(){n.d=function(e,t){for(var a in t)n.o(t,a)&&!n.o(e,a)&&Object.defineProperty(e,a,{enumerable:!0,get:t[a]})}}(),function(){n.g=function(){if("object"===typeof globalThis)return globalThis;try{return this||new Function("return this")()}catch(e){if("object"===typeof window)return window}}()}(),function(){n.o=function(e,t){return Object.prototype.hasOwnProperty.call(e,t)}}(),function(){n.r=function(e){"undefined"!==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.toStringTag&&Object.defineProperty(e,Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"}),Object.defineProperty(e,"__esModule",{value:!0})}}(),function(){var e={143:0};n.O.j=function(t){return 0===e[t]};var t=function(t,a){var o,i,r=a[0],s=a[1],c=a[2],l=0;if(r.some((function(t){return 0!==e[t]}))){for(o in s)n.o(s,o)&&(n.m[o]=s[o]);if(c)var h=c(n)}for(t&&t(a);l<r.length;l++)i=r[l],n.o(e,i)&&e[i]&&e[i][0](),e[i]=0;return n.O(h)},a=self["webpackChunkmdbox_ham_radio_exam"]=self["webpackChunkmdbox_ham_radio_exam"]||[];a.forEach(t.bind(null,0)),a.push=t.bind(null,a.push.bind(a))}();var a=n.O(void 0,[998],(function(){return n(8115)}));a=n.O(a)})();
//# sourceMappingURL=app.e115099f.js.map